Why don't you go ahead?
Sit down and see if you can get comfy.
-You good? All right.
-Yeah.
Um...
Take one, marker.
Wanna start
by introducing yourself?
Hello, world. Bailey. Take three.
You good?
-This is the worst part, man.
I don't like this.
I worked at Facebook in 2011 and 2012.
I was one of the really early employees
at Instagram.
I worked at, uh, Google,
uh, YouTube.
Apple, Google, Twitter, Palm.
I helped start Mozilla Labs
and switched over to the Firefox side.
Are we rolling? Everybody?
Great.
I worked at Twitter.
My last job there
was the senior vice president
of engineering.
I was the president of Pinterest.
Before that, um,
I was the... the director of monetization
at Facebook for five years.
While at Twitter, I spent a number
of years running their developer platform,
and then I became
head of consumer product.
I was the coinventor of Google Drive,
Gmail Chat,
Facebook Pages,
and the Facebook like button.
Yeah. This is... This is why I spent,
like, eight months
talking back and forth with lawyers.
This freaks me out.
When I was there,
I always felt like,
fundamentally, it was a force for good.
I don't know if I feel that way anymore.
I left Google in June 2017, uh,
due to ethical concerns.
And... And not just at Google
but within the industry at large.
I'm very concerned.
It's easy today to lose sight of the fact
that these tools actually have created
some wonderful things in the world.
They've reunited lost family members.
They've found organ donors.
I mean, there were meaningful,
systemic changes happening
around the world
because of these platforms
that were positive!
I think we were naive
about the flip side of that coin.
Yeah, these things, you release them,
and they take on a life of their own.
And how they're used is pretty different
than how you expected.
Nobody, I deeply believe,
ever intended any of these consequences.
There's no one bad guy.
No. Absolutely not.
So, then,
what's the... what's the problem?
Is there a problem,
and what is the problem?
Yeah, it is hard
to give a single, succinct...
I'm trying to touch on
many different problems.
What is the problem?
the so-called Big Tech names
are getting bigger.
The entire tech industry is
under a new level of scrutiny.
And a new study sheds light on the link
between mental health
and social media use.
...is going on
that gets no coverage at all.
Tens of millions of Americans
are hopelessly addicted
to their electronic devices.
It's exacerbated by the fact
that you can literally isolate yourself
now
in a bubble, thanks to our technology.
Fake news is becoming more advanced
and threatening societies
around the world.
We weren't expecting any of this
when we created Twitter over 12 years ago.
White House officials say
they have no reason to believe
the Russian cyberattacks will stop.
YouTube is being forced
to concentrate on cleansing the site.
TikTok,
if you talk to any tween out there...
...there's no chance
they'll delete this thing...
Hey, Isla,
can you get the table ready, please?
There's a question
about whether social media
is making your child depressed.
Isla,
can you set the table, please?
These cosmetic procedures
are becoming so popular with teens,
plastic surgeons have coined
a new syndrome for it,
"Snapchat dysmorphia,"
with young patients wanting surgery
so they can look more like they do
in filtered selfies.
Still don't see why you let her have
that thing.
What was I supposed to do?
I mean, every other kid
in her class had one.
She's only 11.
Cass, no one's forcing you to get one.
You can stay disconnected
as long as you want.
Hey, I'm connected without a cell phone,
okay? I'm on the Internet right now.
Also, that isn't even actual connection.
It's just a load of sh--
Surveillance capitalism has come to shape
our politics and culture
in ways many people don't perceive.
and now white supremacists
are doing the same.
Recently in India,
Internet lynch mobs have killed
a dozen people, including these five...
It's not just fake news;
it's fake news with consequences.
How do you handle an epidemic
in the age of fake news?
Can you get the coronavirus
by eating Chinese food?
We have gone from the information age
into the disinformation age.
Our democracy is under assault.
What I said was,
"I think the tools
that have been created today are starting
to erode the social fabric
of how society works."
Fine.
Aza does
welcoming remarks. We play the video.
And then, "Ladies and gentlemen,
Tristan Harris."
-Right.
Great.
So, I come up, and...
basically say, "Thank you all for coming."
Um...
So, today, I wanna talk about a new agenda
for technology.
And why we wanna do that
is because if you ask people,
"What's wrong in the tech industry
right now?"
there's a cacophony of grievances
and scandals,
and "They stole our data."
And there's tech addiction.
And there's fake news.
And there's polarization
and some elections
that are getting hacked.
But is there something
that is beneath all these problems
that's causing all these things
to happen at once?
-Does this feel good?
-Very good. Yeah.
Um...
I'm just trying to...
Like, I want people to see...
Like, there's a problem happening
in the tech industry,
and it doesn't have a name,
and it has to do with one source,
like, one...
When you look around you,
it feels like the world is going crazy.
You have to ask yourself, like,
"Is this normal?
Or have we all fallen under some kind
of spell?"
I wish more people could understand
how this works
because it shouldn't be something
that only the tech industry knows.
It should be something
that everybody knows.
Bye.
Here you go, sir.
Hello!
Hi.
-Tristan. Nice to meet you.
right?
-Yes.
-Awesome. Cool.
Tristan Harris
is a former design ethicist for Google
and has been called the closest thing
Silicon Valley has to a conscience.
He's asking tech
to bring what he calls "ethical design"
to its products.
It's rare
for a tech insider to be so blunt,
but Tristan Harris believes
someone needs to be.
When I was at Google,
I was on the Gmail team,
and I just started getting burnt out
'cause we'd had
so many conversations about...
you know, what the inbox should look like
and what color it should be, and...
And I, you know, felt personally addicted
to e-mail,
and I found it fascinating
there was no one at Gmail working
on making it less addictive.
And I was like,
"Is anybody else thinking about this?
I haven't heard anybody talk about this."
-And I was feeling this frustration...
...with the tech industry, overall,
that we'd kind of, like, lost our way.
You know, I really struggled
to try and figure out
how, from the inside, we could change it.
And that was when I decided
to make a presentation,
kind of a call to arms.
Every day, I went home and I worked on it
for a couple hours every single night.
It basically just said,
you know,
never before
in history have 50 designers--
20- to 35-year-old white guys
in California--
made decisions that would have an impact
on two billion people.
Two billion people will have thoughts
that they didn't intend to have
because a designer at Google said,
"This is how notifications work
on that screen that you wake up to
in the morning."
And we have a moral responsibility,
as Google, for solving this problem.
And I sent this presentation
to about 15, 20 of my closest colleagues
at Google,
and I was very nervous about it.
I wasn't sure how it was gonna land.
When I went to work the next day,
most of the laptops
had the presentation open.
Later that day, there was, like,
400 simultaneous viewers,
so it just kept growing and growing.
I got e-mails from all around the company.
I mean, people in every department saying,
"I totally agree."
"I see this affecting my kids."
"I see this affecting
the people around me."
"We have to do something about this."
It felt like I was sort of launching
a revolution or something like that.
Later, I found out Larry Page
had been notified about this presentation
-in three separate meetings that day.
And so, it created
this kind of cultural moment
-that Google needed to take seriously.
And then... nothing.
Everyone in 2006...
including all of us at Facebook,
just had total admiration for Google
and what Google had built,
which was this incredibly useful service
that did, far as we could tell,
lots of goodness for the world,
and they built
this parallel money machine.
We had such envy for that,
and it seemed so elegant to us...
and so perfect.
Facebook had been around
for about two years,
um, and I was hired to come in
and figure out
what the business model was gonna be
for the company.
I was the director of monetization.
The point was, like,
"You're the person who's gonna figure out
how this thing monetizes."
And there were a lot of people
who did a lot of the work,
but I was clearly one of the people
who was pointing towards...
"Well, we have to make money, A...
and I think this advertising model
is probably the most elegant way.
Uh-oh. What's this video Mom just sent us?
Oh, that's from a talk show,
but that's pretty good.
Guy's kind of a genius.
He's talking all about deleting
social media, which you gotta do.
I might have to start blocking
her e-mails.
I don't even know
what she's talking about, man.
She's worse than I am.
-No, she only uses it for recipes.
-Right, and work.
-And workout videos.
And to check up on us.
And everyone else she's ever met
in her entire life.
If you are scrolling through
your social media feed
while you're watchin' us, you need to put
the damn phone down and listen up
'cause our next guest has written
an incredible book
about how much it's wrecking our lives.
Please welcome author
Ten Arguments for Deleting
Your Social Media Accounts Right Now...
Uh-huh.
-...Jaron Lanier.
Companies like Google and Facebook
are some of the wealthiest
and most successful of all time.
Uh, they have relatively few employees.
They just have this giant computer
that rakes in money, right? Uh...
Now, what are they being paid for?
So, I've been an investor
in technology for 35 years.
The first 50 years of Silicon Valley,
the industry made products--
hardware, software--
sold 'em to customers.
Nice, simple business.
For the last ten years,
the biggest companies in Silicon Valley
have been in the business
of selling their users.
It's a little even trite to say now,
but... because we don't pay
for the products that we use,
advertisers pay
for the products that we use.
Advertisers are the customers.
We're the thing being sold.
The classic saying is:
"If you're not paying for the product,
then you are the product."
A lot of people think, you know,
"Oh, well, Google's just a search box,
and Facebook's just a place to see
what my friends are doing
and see their photos."
But what they don't realize
is they're competing for your attention.
So, you know, Facebook, Snapchat,
Twitter, Instagram, YouTube,
companies like this, their business model
is to keep people engaged on the screen.
Let's figure out how to get
as much of this person's attention
as we possibly can.
How much time can we get you to spend?
How much of your life can we get you
to give to us?
When you think about
how some of these companies work,
it starts to make sense.
There are all these services
on the Internet that we think of as free,
but they're not free.
They're paid for by advertisers.
Why do advertisers pay those companies?
They pay in exchange for showing their ads
to us.
We're the product. Our attention
is the product being sold to advertisers.
That's a little too simplistic.
It's the gradual, slight,
imperceptible change
in your own behavior and perception
that is the product.
the product.
It's the only possible product.
There's nothing else on the table
that could possibly be called the product.
That's the only thing there is
for them to make money from.
Changing what you do,
how you think, who you are.
It's a gradual change. It's slight.
If you can go to somebody and you say,
"Give me $10 million,
and I will change the world one percent
in the direction you want it to change..."
It's the world! That can be incredible,
and that's worth a lot of money.
Okay.
This is what every business
has always dreamt of:
to have a guarantee that if it places
an ad, it will be successful.
That's their business.
They sell certainty.
In order to be successful
in that business,
you have to have great predictions.
Great predictions begin
with one imperative:
you need a lot of data.
Many people call this
surveillance capitalism,
capitalism profiting
off of the infinite tracking
of everywhere everyone goes
by large technology companies
whose business model is to make sure
that advertisers are as successful
as possible.
This is a new kind of marketplace now.
It's a marketplace
that never existed before.
And it's a marketplace
that trades exclusively in human futures.
Just like there are markets that trade
in pork belly futures or oil futures.
We now have markets
that trade in human futures at scale,
and those markets have produced
the trillions of dollars
that have made the Internet companies
the richest companies
in the history of humanity.
What I want people to know
is that everything they're doing online
being tracked,
being measured.
Every single action you take
is carefully monitored and recorded.
Exactly what image you stop and look at,
for how long you look at it.
Oh, yeah, seriously,
They know
when people are lonely.
They know when people are depressed.
They know when people are looking
at photos of your ex-romantic partners.
They know what you're doing late at night.
They know the entire thing.
Whether you're an introvert
or an extrovert,
or what kind of neuroses you have,
what your personality type is like.
They have more information
about us
than has ever been imagined
in human history.
It is unprecedented.
And so, all of this data that we're...
that we're just pouring out all the time
is being fed into these systems
that have almost no human supervision
and that are making better and better
and better and better predictions
about what we're gonna do
and... and who we are.
People have the misconception
it's our data being sold.
It's not in Facebook's business interest
to give up the data.
What do they do with that data?
They build models
that predict our actions,
and whoever has the best model wins.
His scrolling speed is slowing.
Nearing the end
of his average session length.
Decreasing ad load.
Pull back on friends and family.
On the other side of the screen,
it's almost as if they had
this avatar voodoo doll-like model of us.
All of the things we've ever done,
all the clicks we've ever made,
all the videos we've watched,
all the likes,
that all gets brought back into building
a more and more accurate model.
The model, once you have it,
you can predict the kinds of things
that person does.
Right, let me just test.
Where you'll go.
I can predict what kind of videos
will keep you watching.
I can predict what kinds of emotions tend
to trigger you.
Yes, perfect.
The most epic fails of the year.
-Perfect. That worked.
-Following with another video.
Beautiful. Let's squeeze in a sneaker ad
before it starts.
At a lot
of technology companies,
there's three main goals.
There's the engagement goal:
to drive up your usage,
to keep you scrolling.
There's the growth goal:
to keep you coming back
and inviting as many friends
and getting them to invite more friends.
And then there's the advertising goal:
to make sure that,
as all that's happening,
we're making as much money as possible
from advertising.
Each of these goals are powered
by algorithms
whose job is to figure out
what to show you
to keep those numbers going up.
We often talked about, at Facebook,
this idea
of being able to just dial that as needed.
And, you know, we talked
about having Mark have those dials.
"Hey, I want more users in Korea today."
"Turn the dial."
"Let's dial up the ads a little bit."
"Dial up monetization, just slightly."
And so, that happ--
I mean, at all of these companies,
there is that level of precision.
-Dude, how--
-I don't know how I didn't get carded.
-That ref just, like, sucked or something.
-You got literally all the way...
-That's Rebecca. Go talk to her.
-I know who it is.
-Dude, yo, go talk to her.
I'm workin' on it.
His calendar says he's on a break
right now. We should be live.
Want me to nudge him?
Yeah, nudge away.
"Your friend Tyler just joined.
Say hi with a wave."
Come on, Ben.
Send a wave.
-You're not... Go talk to her, dude.
New link! All right, we're on.
Follow that up with a post
from User 079044238820, Rebecca.
Good idea. GPS coordinates indicate
that they're in close proximity.
He's primed for an ad.
Auction time.
Sold! To Deep Fade hair wax.
We had 468 interested bidders. We sold Ben
at 3.262 cents for an impression.
We've created a world
in which online connection
has become primary,
especially for younger generations.
And yet, in that world,
any time two people connect,
the only way it's financed
is through a sneaky third person
who's paying to manipulate
those two people.
So, we've created
an entire global generation of people
who are raised within a context
where the very meaning of communication,
the very meaning of culture,
is manipulation.
We've put deceit and sneakiness
at the absolute center
of everything we do.
Grab the...
Okay.
-Where's it help to hold it?
Great.
Here?
Yeah.
How does this come across on camera
if I were to do, like, this move--
We can--
Like that?
What?
-Yeah.
Do that again.
-Exactly. Yeah.
Yeah. No, it's probably not...
Like... yeah.
I mean, this one is less...
Larissa's, like,
actually freaking out over here.
Is that good?
I was, like, five years old
when I learned how to do magic.
And I could fool adults,
fully-grown adults with, like, PhDs.
Magicians were almost like
the first neuroscientists
and psychologists.
Like, they were the ones
who first understood
how people's minds work.
They just, in real time, are testing
lots and lots of stuff on people.
A magician understands something,
some part of your mind
that we're not aware of.
That's what makes the illusion work.
Doctors, lawyers, people who know
how to build 747s or nuclear missiles,
they don't know more about
how their own mind is vulnerable.
That's a separate discipline.
And it's a discipline
that applies to all human beings.
From that perspective, you can have
a very different understanding
of what technology is doing.
When I was
at the Stanford Persuasive Technology Lab,
this is what we learned.
How could you use everything we know
about the psychology
of what persuades people
and build that into technology?
Now, many of you in the audience
are geniuses already.
I think that's true, but my goal is
to turn you into a behavior-change genius.
There are many prominent Silicon Valley
figures who went through that class--
key growth figures at Facebook and Uber
and... and other companies--
and learned how to make technology
more persuasive,
Tristan being one.
Persuasive technology
is just sort of design
intentionally applied to the extreme,
where we really want to modify
someone's behavior.
We want them to take this action.
We want them to keep doing this
with their finger.
You pull down and you refresh,
it's gonna be a new thing at the top.
Pull down and refresh again, it's new.
Every single time.
Which, in psychology, we call
a positive intermittent reinforcement.
You don't know when you're gonna get it
or if you're gonna get something,
which operates just like the slot machines
in Vegas.
It's not enough
that you use the product consciously,
I wanna dig down deeper
into the brain stem
and implant, inside of you,
an unconscious habit
so that you are being programmed
at a deeper level.
You don't even realize it.
A man, James Marshall...
Every time you see it there
on the counter,
and you just look at it,
and you know if you reach over,
it just might have something for you,
so you play that slot machine
to see what you got, right?
That's not by accident.
That's a design technique.
He brings a golden nugget
to an officer
in the army in San Francisco.
Mind you, the... the population
of San Francisco was only...
The secret didn't last.
So, if you get an e-mail
that says your friend just tagged you
in a photo,
of course you're going to click
on that e-mail and look at the photo.
It's not something
you can just decide to ignore.
This is deep-seated, like,
human personality
that they're tapping into.
What you should be asking yourself is:
"Why doesn't that e-mail contain
the photo in it?
It would be a lot easier
to see the photo."
When Facebook found that feature,
they just dialed the hell out of that
because they said, "This is gonna be
a great way to grow activity.
Let's just get people tagging each other
in photos all day long."
He commented.
Nice.
Okay, Rebecca received it,
and she is responding.
All right, let Ben know that she's typing
so we don't lose him.
Activating ellipsis.
Great, she posted.
He's commenting on her comment
about his comment on her post.
Hold on, he stopped typing.
Let's autofill.
Emojis. He loves emojis.
He went with fire.
There's an entire discipline
and field called "growth hacking."
Teams of engineers
whose job is to hack people's psychology
so they can get more growth.
They can get more user sign-ups,
more engagement.
They can get you to invite more people.
After all the testing, all the iterating,
all of this stuff,
you know the single biggest thing
we realized?
Get any individual to seven friends
in ten days.
That was it.
Chamath was the head of growth at Facebook
early on,
and he's very well known
in the tech industry
for pioneering a lot of the growth tactics
that were used to grow Facebook
at incredible speed.
And those growth tactics have then become
the standard playbook for Silicon Valley.
They were used at Uber
and at a bunch of other companies.
One of the things that he pioneered
was the use of scientific A/B testing
of small feature changes.
Companies like Google and Facebook
would roll out
lots of little, tiny experiments
that they were constantly doing on users.
And over time,
by running these constant experiments,
you... you develop the most optimal way
to get users to do
what you want them to do.
It's... It's manipulation.
a lab rat. We're all lab rats.
And it's not like we're lab rats
for developing a cure for cancer.
It's not like they're trying
us.
Right? We're just zombies,
and they want us to look at more ads
so they can make more money.
Facebook conducted
what they called
"massive-scale contagion experiments."
Okay.
How do we use subliminal cues
on the Facebook pages
to get more people to go vote
in the midterm elections?
And they discovered
that they were able to do that.
One thing they concluded
is that we now know
we can affect real-world behavior
and emotions
without ever triggering
the user's awareness.
They are completely clueless.
We're pointing these engines of AI
back at ourselves
to reverse-engineer what elicits responses
from us.
Almost like you're stimulating nerve cells
on a spider
to see what causes its legs to respond.
So, it really is
this kind of prison experiment
where we're just, you know,
roping people into the matrix,
and we're just harvesting all this money
and... and data from all their activity
to profit from.
And we're not even aware
that it's happening.
So, we want to psychologically figure out
how to manipulate you as fast as possible
and then give you back that dopamine hit.
We did that brilliantly at Facebook.
Instagram has done it.
WhatsApp has done it.
You know, Snapchat has done it.
Twitter has done it.
I mean, it's exactly the kind of thing
that a... that a hacker like myself
would come up with
because you're exploiting a vulnerability
in... in human psychology.
And I just...
I think that we...
you know, the inventors, creators...
uh, you know, and it's me, it's Mark,
it's the...
you know, Kevin Systrom at Instagram...
It's all of these people...
um, understood this consciously,
and we did it anyway.
No one got upset when bicycles showed up.
Right? Like, if everyone's starting
to go around on bicycles,
no one said,
"Oh, my God, we've just ruined society.
They're pulling people
away from their kids.
They're ruining the fabric of democracy.
People can't tell what's true."
Like, we never said any of that stuff
about a bicycle.
If something is a tool,
it genuinely is just sitting there,
waiting patiently.
If something is not a tool,
it's demanding things from you.
It's seducing you. It's manipulating you.
It wants things from you.
And we've moved away from having
a tools-based technology environment
to an addiction- and manipulation-based
technology environment.
That's what's changed.
Social media isn't a tool
that's just waiting to be used.
It has its own goals,
and it has its own means of pursuing them
by using your psychology against you.
Rewind a few years ago,
I was the...
I was the president of Pinterest.
I was coming home,
and I couldn't get off my phone
once I got home,
despite having two young kids
who needed my love and attention.
I was in the pantry, you know,
typing away on an e-mail
or sometimes looking at Pinterest.
I thought, "God, this is classic irony.
I am going to work during the day
and building something
that then I am falling prey to."
And I couldn't... I mean, some
of those moments, I couldn't help myself.
The one
that I'm... I'm most prone to is Twitter.
Uh, used to be Reddit.
I actually had to write myself software
to break my addiction to reading Reddit.
I'm probably most addicted to my e-mail.
I mean, really. I mean, I... I feel it.
Well, I mean, it's sort-- it's interesting
that knowing what was going on
behind the curtain,
I still wasn't able to control my usage.
So, that's a little scary.
Even knowing how these tricks work,
I'm still susceptible to them.
I'll still pick up the phone,
and 20 minutes will disappear.
Do you check your smartphone
before you pee in the morning
or while you're peeing in the morning?
'Cause those are the only two choices.
I tried through willpower,
just pure willpower...
"I'll put down my phone, I'll leave
my phone in the car when I get home."
I think I told myself a thousand times,
a thousand different days,
"I am not gonna bring my phone
to the bedroom,"
and then 9:00 p.m. rolls around.
"Well, I wanna bring my phone
in the bedroom."
Willpower was kind of attempt one,
and then attempt two was,
you know, brute force.
Introducing the Kitchen Safe.
The Kitchen Safe is a revolutionary,
new, time-locking container
that helps you fight temptation.
All David has to do is place
those temptations in the Kitchen Safe.
Next, he rotates the dial
to set the timer.
And, finally, he presses the dial
to activate the lock.
The Kitchen Safe is great...
We have that, don't we?
...video games, credit cards,
and cell phones.
Yeah, we do.
Once the Kitchen Safe
is locked, it cannot be opened
until the timer reaches zero.
So, here's the thing.
Social media is a drug.
I mean,
we have a basic biological imperative
to connect with other people.
That directly affects the release
of dopamine in the reward pathway.
Millions of years of evolution, um,
are behind that system
to get us to come together
and live in communities,
to find mates, to propagate our species.
So, there's no doubt
that a vehicle like social media,
which optimizes this connection
between people,
is going to have the potential
for addiction.
-Mmm!
-Dad, stop!
I have, like, 1,000 more snips
to send before dinner.
Snips?
-I don't know what a snip is.
-Mm, that smells good, baby.
-All right. Thank you.
I was, um, thinking we could use
all five senses
to enjoy our dinner tonight.
So, I decided that we're not gonna have
any cell phones at the table tonight.
So, turn 'em in.
-Really?
Yep.
-All right.
-Thank you. Ben?
-Okay.
-Mom, the phone pirate.
-Got it.
-Mom!
So, they will be safe in here
until after dinner...
-and everyone can just chill out.
Okay?
-Can I just see who it is?
-No.
Just gonna go get another fork.
Thank you.
Honey, you can't open that.
I locked it for an hour,
so just leave it alone.
So, what should we talk about?
Well, we could talk
about the, uh, Extreme Center wackos
I drove by today.
Please, Frank.
-What?
I don't wanna talk about politics.
-What's wrong with the Extreme Center?
-See? He doesn't even get it.
It depends on who you ask.
It's like asking,
"What's wrong with propaganda?"
Isla!
Oh, my God.
Do you want me to...
Yeah.
I... I'm worried about my kids.
And if you have kids,
I'm worried about your kids.
Armed with all the knowledge that I have
and all of the experience,
I am fighting my kids about the time
that they spend on phones
and on the computer.
I will say to my son, "How many hours do
you think you're spending on your phone?"
He'll be like, "It's, like, half an hour.
It's half an hour, tops."
I'd say upwards hour, hour and a half.
I looked at his screen report
a couple weeks ago.
-Three hours and 45 minutes.
That...
I don't think that's...
No. Per day, on average?
-Yeah.
-Should I go get it right now?
There's not a day that goes by
that I don't remind my kids
about the pleasure-pain balance,
about dopamine deficit states,
about the risk of addiction.
Moment of truth.
Two hours, 50 minutes per day.
-Let's see.
-Actually, I've been using a lot today.
-Last seven days.
-That's probably why.
Instagram, six hours, 13 minutes.
Okay, so my Instagram's worse.
My screen's completely shattered.
Thanks, Cass.
What do you mean, "Thanks, Cass"?
You keep freaking Mom out about our phones
when it's not really a problem.
We don't need our phones to eat dinner!
I get what you're saying.
It's just not that big a deal. It's not.
If it's not that big a deal,
don't use it for a week.
Yeah. Yeah, actually, if you can put
that thing away for, like, a whole week...
I will buy you a new screen.
-Like, starting now?
Starting now.
-Okay. You got a deal.
Okay.
Okay, you gotta leave it here, though,
buddy.
All right, I'm plugging it in.
Let the record show... I'm backing away.
Okay.
-You're on the clock.
One week.
Oh, my...
Think he can do it?
I don't know. We'll see.
Just eat, okay?
Good family dinner!
These technology products
were not designed
by child psychologists who are trying
to protect and nurture children.
They were just designing
to make these algorithms
that were really good at recommending
the next video to you
or really good at getting you
to take a photo with a filter on it.
It's not just
that it's controlling
where they spend their attention.
Especially social media starts to dig
deeper and deeper down into the brain stem
and take over kids' sense of self-worth
and identity.
We evolved to care about
whether other people in our tribe...
think well of us or not
'cause it matters.
But were we evolved to be aware
of what 10,000 people think of us?
We were not evolved
to have social approval being dosed to us
every five minutes.
That was not at all what we were built
to experience.
We curate our lives
around this perceived sense of perfection
because we get rewarded
in these short-term signals--
hearts, likes, thumbs-up--
and we conflate that with value,
and we conflate it with truth.
And instead, what it really is
is fake, brittle popularity...
that's short-term and that leaves you
even more, and admit it,
vacant and empty before you did it.
Because then it forces you
into this vicious cycle
where you're like, "What's the next thing
I need to do now? 'Cause I need it back."
Think about that compounded
by two billion people,
and then think about how people react then
to the perceptions of others.
It's just a... It's really bad.
It's really, really bad.
There has been
a gigantic increase
in depression and anxiety
for American teenagers
which began right around...
between 2011 and 2013.
The number of teenage girls out of 100,000
in this country
who were admitted to a hospital every year
because they cut themselves
or otherwise harmed themselves,
that number was pretty stable
until around 2010, 2011,
and then it begins going way up.
It's up 62 percent for older teen girls.
It's up 189 percent for the preteen girls.
That's nearly triple.
Even more horrifying,
we see the same pattern with suicide.
The older teen girls, 15 to 19 years old,
they're up 70 percent,
compared to the first decade
of this century.
The preteen girls,
who have very low rates to begin with,
they are up 151 percent.
And that pattern points to social media.
Gen Z, the kids born after 1996 or so,
those kids are the first generation
in history
that got on social media in middle school.
How do they spend their time?
They come home from school,
and they're on their devices.
A whole generation is more anxious,
more fragile, more depressed.
They're much less comfortable
taking risks.
The rates at which they get
driver's licenses have been dropping.
The number
who have ever gone out on a date
or had any kind of romantic interaction
is dropping rapidly.
This is a real change in a generation.
And remember, for every one of these,
for every hospital admission,
there's a family that is traumatized
and horrified.
"My God, what is happening to our kids?"
It's plain as day to me.
These services are killing people...
and causing people to kill themselves.
I don't know any parent who says, "Yeah,
I really want my kids to be growing up
feeling manipulated by tech designers, uh,
manipulating their attention,
making it impossible to do their homework,
making them compare themselves
to unrealistic standards of beauty."
Like, no one wants that.
No one does.
We... We used to have these protections.
When children watched
Saturday morning cartoons,
we cared about protecting children.
We would say, "You can't advertise
to these age children in these ways."
But then you take YouTube for Kids,
and it gobbles up that entire portion
of the attention economy,
and now all kids are exposed
to YouTube for Kids.
And all those protections
and all those regulations are gone.
We're training and conditioning
a whole new generation of people...
that when we are uncomfortable or lonely
or uncertain or afraid,
we have a digital pacifier for ourselves
that is kind of atrophying our own ability
to deal with that.
Photoshop didn't have
1,000 engineers
on the other side of the screen,
using notifications, using your friends,
using AI to predict what's gonna
perfectly addict you, or hook you,
or manipulate you, or allow advertisers
to test 60,000 variations
of text or colors to figure out
what's the perfect manipulation
of your mind.
This is a totally new species
of power and influence.
I... I would say, again, the methods used
to play on people's ability
to be addicted or to be influenced
may be different this time,
and they probably are different.
They were different when newspapers
came in and the printing press came in,
and they were different
when television came in,
and you had three major networks and...
-At the time.
-At the time. That's what I'm saying.
But I'm saying the idea
that there's a new level
and that new level has happened
so many times before.
I mean, this is just the latest new level
that we've seen.
There's this narrative that, you know,
"We'll just adapt to it.
We'll learn how to live
with these devices,
just like we've learned how to live
with everything else."
And what this misses
is there's something distinctly new here.
Perhaps the most dangerous piece
of all this is the fact
that it's driven by technology
that's advancing exponentially.
Roughly, if you say from, like,
the 1960s to today,
processing power has gone up
about a trillion times.
Nothing else that we have has improved
at anything near that rate.
Like, cars are, you know,
roughly twice as fast.
And almost everything else is negligible.
And perhaps most importantly,
our human-- our physiology,
our brains have evolved not at all.
Human beings, at a mind and body
and sort of physical level,
are not gonna fundamentally change.
I know, but they...
We can do genetic engineering
and develop new kinds of human beings,
but realistically speaking,
you're living inside of hardware, a brain,
that was, like, millions of years old,
and then there's this screen, and then
on the opposite side of the screen,
there's these thousands of engineers
and supercomputers
that have goals that are different
than your goals,
and so, who's gonna win in that game?
Who's gonna win?
How are we losing?
-I don't know.
-Where is he? This is not normal.
Did I overwhelm him
with friends and family content?
-Probably.
-Well, maybe it was all the ads.
No. Something's very wrong.
Let's switch to resurrection mode.
When you think of AI,
you know, an AI's gonna ruin the world,
and you see, like, a Terminator,
and you see Arnold Schwarzenegger.
I'll be back.
You see drones,
and you think, like,
"Oh, we're gonna kill people with AI."
And what people miss is that AI
already runs today's world right now.
Even talking about "an AI"
is just a metaphor.
At these companies like... like Google,
there's just massive, massive rooms,
some of them underground,
some of them underwater,
of just computers.
Tons and tons of computers,
as far as the eye can see.
They're deeply interconnected
with each other
and running
extremely complicated programs,
sending information back and forth
between each other all the time.
And they'll be running
many different programs,
many different products
on those same machines.
Some of those things could be described
as simple algorithms,
some could be described as algorithms
that are so complicated,
you would call them intelligence.
embedded in code...
and that algorithms are not objective.
Algorithms are optimized
to some definition of success.
So, if you can imagine,
if a... if a commercial enterprise builds
an algorithm
to their definition of success,
it's a commercial interest.
It's usually profit.
You are giving the computer
the goal state, "I want this outcome,"
and then the computer itself is learning
how to do it.
That's where the term "machine learning"
comes from.
And so, every day, it gets slightly better
at picking the right posts
in the right order
so that you spend longer and longer
in that product.
And no one really understands
what they're doing
in order to achieve that goal.
The algorithm has a mind of its own,
so even though a person writes it,
it's written in a way
that you kind of build the machine,
and then the machine changes itself.
There's only a handful of people
at these companies,
at Facebook and Twitter
and other companies...
There's only a few people who understand
how those systems work,
and even they don't necessarily
fully understand
what's gonna happen
with a particular piece of content.
So, as humans, we've almost lost control
over these systems.
Because they're controlling, you know,
the information that we see,
they're controlling us more
than we're controlling them.
against comparables
in his geographic zone.
His psychometric doppelgangers.
There are 13,694 people
behaving just like him in his region.
-What's trending with them?
-We need something actually good
for a proper resurrection,
given that the typical stuff
isn't working.
Not even that cute girl from school.
My analysis shows that going political
with Extreme Center content
has a 62.3 percent chance
of long-term engagement.
That's not bad.
It's not good enough to lead with.
Okay, okay, so we've tried notifying him
about tagged photos,
invitations, current events,
even a direct message from Rebecca.
But what about User 01265923010?
Yeah, Ben loved all of her posts.
For months and, like,
literally all of them, and then nothing.
I calculate a 92.3 percent chance
of resurrection
with a notification about Ana.
And her new friend.
Oh, you gotta be kiddin' me.
Uh...
Okay.
-What?
Bam! We're back!
Let's get back to making money, boys.
Yes, and connecting Ben
with the entire world.
I'm giving him access
to all the information he might like.
Hey, do you guys ever wonder if, you know,
like, the feed is good for Ben?
-No.
♪
♪ Ah! ♪
I can't stand it
♪
♪ You're mine ♪
So, imagine you're on Facebook...
and you're effectively playing
against this artificial intelligence
that knows everything about you,
can anticipate your next move,
and you know literally nothing about it,
except that there are cat videos
and birthdays on it.
That's not a fair fight.
Ben and Jerry, it's time to go, bud!
Ben?
Ben.
Mm.
Come on.
School time.
Let's go.
How you doing today?
-Oh, I'm... I'm nervous.
-Are ya?
-Yeah.
when technology would overwhelm
human strengths and intelligence.
When is it gonna cross the singularity,
replace our jobs, be smarter than humans?
But there's this much earlier moment...
when technology exceeds
and overwhelms human weaknesses.
This point being crossed
is at the root of addiction,
polarization, radicalization,
outrage-ification,
vanity-ification, the entire thing.
This is overpowering human nature,
and this is checkmate on humanity.
I'm sorry.
One of the ways
I try to get people to understand
just how wrong feeds from places
like Facebook are
is to think about the Wikipedia.
When you go to a page, you're seeing
the same thing as other people.
So, it's one of the few things online
that we at least hold in common.
Now, just imagine for a second
that Wikipedia said,
"We're gonna give each person
a different customized definition,
and we're gonna be paid by people
for that."
So, Wikipedia would be spying on you.
Wikipedia would calculate,
"What's the thing I can do
to get this person to change a little bit
on behalf of some commercial interest?"
Right?
And then it would change the entry.
Can you imagine that?
Well, you should be able to,
'cause that's exactly what's happening
on Facebook.
It's exactly what's happening
in your YouTube feed.
When you go to Google and type in
"Climate change is,"
you're going to see different results
depending on where you live.
In certain cities,
you're gonna see it autocomplete
with "climate change is a hoax."
In other cases, you're gonna see
"climate change is causing the destruction
of nature."
And that's a function not
of what the truth is about climate change,
but about
where you happen to be Googling from
and the particular things
Google knows about your interests.
Even two friends
who are so close to each other,
who have almost the exact same set
of friends,
they think, you know,
"I'm going to news feeds on Facebook.
I'll see the exact same set of updates."
But it's not like that at all.
They see completely different worlds
because they're based
on these computers calculating
what's perfect for each of them.
The way to think about it
Truman Shows.
Each person has their own reality,
with their own...
facts.
Why do you think
that, uh, Truman has never come close
to discovering the true nature
of his world until now?
We accept the reality of the world
with which we're presented.
It's as simple as that.
Over time, you have the false sense
that everyone agrees with you,
because everyone in your news feed
sounds just like you.
And that once you're in that state,
it turns out you're easily manipulated,
the same way you would be manipulated
by a magician.
A magician shows you a card trick
and says, "Pick a card, any card."
What you don't realize
was that they've done a set-up,
so you pick the card
they want you to pick.
And that's how Facebook works.
Facebook sits there and says,
"Hey, you pick your friends.
You pick the links that you follow."
But that's all nonsense.
It's just like the magician.
Facebook is in charge of your news feed.
We all simply are operating
on a different set of facts.
When that happens at scale,
you're no longer able to reckon with
or even consume information
that contradicts with that world view
that you've created.
That means we aren't actually being
objective,
constructive individuals.
Open up your eyes,
don't believe the lies! Open up...
And then you look
over at the other side,
and you start to think,
"How can those people be so stupid?
Look at all of this information
that I'm constantly seeing.
How are they not seeing
that same information?"
And the answer is, "They're not seeing
that same information."
What are Republicans like?
-People that don't have a clue.
The Democrat Party is a crime syndicate,
not a real political party.
A huge new Pew Research Center study
of 10,000 American adults
finds us more divided than ever,
with personal and political polarization
at a 20-year high.
You have
more than a third of Republicans saying
the Democratic Party is a threat
to the nation,
more than a quarter of Democrats saying
the same thing about the Republicans.
So many of the problems
that we're discussing,
like, around political polarization
exist in spades on cable television.
The media has this exact same problem,
where their business model, by and large,
is that they're selling our attention
to advertisers.
And the Internet is just a new,
even more efficient way to do that.
At YouTube, I was working
on YouTube recommendations.
It worries me that an algorithm
that I worked on
is actually increasing polarization
in society.
But from the point of view of watch time,
this polarization is extremely efficient
at keeping people online.
The only reason
these teachers are teaching this stuff
is 'cause they're getting paid to.
-It's absolutely absurd.
Hey, Benji.
No soccer practice today?
Oh, there is. I'm just catching up
on some news stuff.
Do research. Anything
that sways from the Extreme Center--
Wouldn't exactly call the stuff
that you're watching news.
You're always talking about how messed up
everything is. So are they.
But that stuff is just propaganda.
Neither is true.
It's all about what makes sense.
Ben, I'm serious.
That stuff is bad for you.
-You should go to soccer practice.
Mm.
I share this stuff because I care.
I care that you are being misled,
and it's not okay. All right?
People think
the algorithm is designed
to give them what they really want,
only it's not.
The algorithm is actually trying to find
a few rabbit holes that are very powerful,
trying to find which rabbit hole
is the closest to your interest.
And then if you start watching
one of those videos,
then it will recommend it
over and over again.
It's not like anybody wants this
to happen.
It's just that this is
what the recommendation system is doing.
So much so that Kyrie Irving,
the famous basketball player,
uh, said he believed the Earth was flat,
and he apologized later
because he blamed it
on a YouTube rabbit hole.
You know, like,
you click the YouTube click
and it goes, like,
how deep the rabbit hole goes.
When he later came on to NPR to say,
"I'm sorry for believing this.
I didn't want to mislead people,"
a bunch of students in a classroom
were interviewed saying,
"The round-Earthers got to him."
The flat-Earth conspiracy theory
was recommended
hundreds of millions of times
by the algorithm.
It's easy to think that it's just
a few stupid people who get convinced,
but the algorithm is getting smarter
and smarter every day.
So, today, they are convincing the people
that the Earth is flat,
you
of something that's false.
On November 7th,
the hashtag "Pizzagate" was born.
Pizzagate...
Oh, boy.
Uh...
I still am not 100 percent sure
how this originally came about,
but the idea that ordering a pizza
meant ordering a trafficked person.
As the groups got bigger on Facebook,
Facebook's recommendation engine
started suggesting to regular users
that they join Pizzagate groups.
So, if a user was, for example,
anti-vaccine or believed in chemtrails
or had indicated to Facebook's algorithms
in some way
that they were prone to belief
in conspiracy theories,
Facebook's recommendation engine
would serve them Pizzagate groups.
Eventually, this culminated in
a man showing up with a gun,
deciding that he was gonna go liberate
the children from the basement
of the pizza place
that did not have a basement.
What were you doing?
Making sure
there was nothing there.
Regarding?
Pedophile ring.
What?
He's talking about Pizzagate.
This is an example of a conspiracy theory
that was propagated
across all social networks.
The social network's
own recommendation engine
is voluntarily serving this up to people
who had never searched
for the term "Pizzagate" in their life.
There's a study, an MIT study,
that fake news on Twitter spreads
six times faster than true news.
What is that world gonna look like
when one has a six-times advantage
to the other one?
You can imagine
these things are sort of like...
they... they tilt the floor
of... of human behavior.
They make some behavior harder
and some easier.
And you're always free
to walk up the hill,
but fewer people do,
and so, at scale, at society's scale,
you really are just tilting the floor
and changing what billions of people think
and do.
We've created a system
that biases towards false information.
Not because we want to,
but because false information makes
the companies more money
than the truth. The truth is boring.
It's a disinformation-for-profit
business model.
You make money the more you allow
unregulated messages
to reach anyone for the best price.
Because climate change? Yeah.
It's a hoax. Yeah, it's real.
That's the point.
The more they talk about it
and the more they divide us,
the more they have the power,
the more...
Facebook has trillions
of these news feed posts.
They can't know what's real
or what's true...
which is why this conversation
is so critical right now.
It's not just COVID-19
that's spreading fast.
There's a flow of misinformation online
about the virus.
The notion
drinking water
will flush coronavirus from your system
is one of several myths about the virus
circulating on social media.
The government planned
this event, created the virus,
and had a simulation
of how the countries would react.
Coronavirus is a... a hoax.
SARS, coronavirus.
And look at when it was made. 2018.
I think the US government started
this shit.
Nobody is sick. Nobody is sick.
Nobody knows anybody who's sick.
Maybe the government is using
the coronavirus as an excuse
to get everyone to stay inside
because something else is happening.
Coronavirus is not killing people,
it's the 5G radiation
that they're pumping out.
People are blowing up
actual physical cell phone towers.
We see Russia and China spreading rumors
and conspiracy theories.
This morning,
panic and protest in Ukraine as...
People have no idea what's true,
and now it's a matter of life and death.
Those sources that are spreading
coronavirus misinformation
have amassed
something like 52 million engagements.
You're saying that silver solution
would be effective.
Well, let's say it hasn't been tested
on this strain of the coronavirus, but...
What we're seeing with COVID
is just an extreme version
of what's happening
across our information ecosystem.
Social media amplifies exponential gossip
and exponential hearsay
to the point
that we don't know what's true,
no matter what issue we care about.
He discovers this.
Ben.
-Are you still on the team?
Mm-hmm.
Okay, well,
I'm gonna get a snack before practice
if you... wanna come.
Hm?
You know, never mind.
Nine out of ten people
are dissatisfied right now.
The EC is like any political movement
in history, when you think about it.
We are standing up, and we are...
we are standing up to this noise.
You are my people. I trust you guys.
-The Extreme Center content is brilliant.
He absolutely loves it.
Running an auction.
840 bidders. He sold for 4.35 cents
to a weapons manufacturer.
Let's promote some of these events.
Upcoming rallies in his geographic zone
later this week.
I've got a new vlogger lined up, too.
And... and, honestly, I'm telling you,
I'm willing to do whatever it takes.
And I mean whatever.
-Subscribe...
Ben?
...and also come back
because I'm telling you, yo...
Some real big things.
One of the problems with Facebook
is that, as a tool of persuasion,
it may be the greatest thing ever created.
Now, imagine what that means in the hands
of a dictator or an authoritarian.
If you want to control the population
of your country,
there has never been a tool
as effective as Facebook.
of governments and other bad actors
weaponizing social media,
um, is that it has led
to real, offline harm.
I think the most prominent example
that's gotten a lot of press
is what's happened in Myanmar.
In Myanmar,
when people think of the Internet,
what they are thinking about is Facebook.
And what often happens is
when people buy their cell phone,
the cell phone shop owner will actually
preload Facebook on there for them
and open an account for them.
And so when people get their phone,
the first thing they open
and the only thing they know how to open
is Facebook.
Well, a new bombshell investigation
exposes Facebook's growing struggle
to tackle hate speech in Myanmar.
Facebook really gave the military
and other bad actors
a new way to manipulate public opinion
and to help incite violence
against the Rohingya Muslims
that included mass killings,
burning of entire villages,
mass rape, and other serious crimes
against humanity
that have now led
to 700,000 Rohingya Muslims
having to flee the country.
It's not
that highly motivated propagandists
haven't existed before.
It's that the platforms make it possible
to spread manipulative narratives
with phenomenal ease,
and without very much money.
If I want to manipulate an election,
I can now go into
a conspiracy theory group on Facebook,
and I can find 100 people
who believe
that the Earth is completely flat
and think it's all this conspiracy theory
that we landed on the moon,
and I can tell Facebook,
"Give me 1,000 users who look like that."
Facebook will happily send me
thousands of users that look like them
that I can now hit
with more conspiracy theories.
-New EC video to promote.
Another ad teed up.
Algorithms
and manipulative politicians
are becoming so expert
at learning how to trigger us,
getting so good at creating fake news
that we absorb as if it were reality,
and confusing us into believing
those lies.
It's as though we have
less and less control
over who we are and what we believe.
...so they can pick sides.
There's lies here,
and there's lies over there.
So they can keep the power,
-so they can control everything.
They can control our minds,
-so that they can keep their secrets.
Imagine a world
where no one believes anything true.
Everyone believes
the government's lying to them.
Everything is a conspiracy theory.
"I shouldn't trust anyone.
I hate the other side."
That's where all this is heading.
The political earthquakes in Europe
continue to rumble.
This time, in Italy and Spain.
Overall, Europe's traditional,
centrist coalition lost its majority
while far right
and far left populist parties made gains.
Back up.
These accounts
were deliberately, specifically attempting
-to sow political discord in Hong Kong.
-All right, Ben.
What does it look like to be a country
that's entire diet is Facebook
and social media?
Democracy crumbled quickly.
Six months.
After that chaos in Chicago,
violent clashes between protesters
and supporters...
Democracy is facing
a crisis of confidence.
What we're seeing is a global assault
on democracy.
Most of the countries
that are targeted are countries
that run democratic elections.
This is happening at scale.
By state actors,
by people with millions of dollars saying,
"I wanna destabilize Kenya.
I wanna destabilize Cameroon.
Oh, Angola? That only costs this much."
An extraordinary election
took place Sunday in Brazil.
With a campaign that's been powered
by social media.
We in the tech industry
have created the tools
to destabilize
and erode the fabric of society
in every country, all at once, everywhere.
You have this in Germany, Spain, France,
Brazil, Australia.
Some of the most "developed nations"
in the world
are now imploding on each other,
and what do they have in common?
Knowing what you know now,
do you believe Facebook impacted
the results of the 2016 election?
You know, it's... the...
the reality is, well, there
were so many different forces at play.
Representatives from Facebook, Twitter,
and Google are back on Capitol Hill
for a second day of testimony
about Russia's interference
in the 2016 election.
The manipulation
by third parties is not a hack.
Right? The Russians didn't hack Facebook.
What they did was they used the tools
that Facebook created
for legitimate advertisers
and legitimate users,
and they applied it
to a nefarious purpose.
One country can manipulate another one
without actually invading
its physical borders.
We're seeing violent images.
It appears to be a dumpster
being pushed around...
But it wasn't
about who you wanted to vote for.
It was about sowing total chaos
and division in society.
Now,
this was in Huntington Beach. A march...
It's about making two sides
who couldn't hear each other anymore,
who didn't want to hear each other
anymore,
who didn't trust each other anymore.
This is a city
where hatred was laid bare
and transformed into racial violence.
Ben!
Cassandra!
-Cass!
-Ben!
Come here! Come here!
Arms up. Arms up.
Get down on your knees. Now, down.
Calm--
-Ben!
Hey! Hands up!
Turn around. On the ground. On the ground!
Do we want this system for sale
to the highest bidder?
For democracy to be completely for sale,
where you can reach any mind you want,
target a lie to that specific population,
and create culture wars?
Do we want that?
We are a nation of people...
that no longer speak to each other.
We are a nation of people
who have stopped being friends with people
because of who they voted for
in the last election.
We are a nation of people
who have isolated ourselves
to only watch channels
that tell us that we're right.
My message here today is that tribalism
is ruining us.
It is tearing our country apart.
It is no way for sane adults to act.
If everyone's entitled to their own facts,
there's really no need for compromise,
no need for people to come together.
In fact, there's really no need
for people to interact.
We need to have...
some shared understanding of reality.
Otherwise, we aren't a country.
So, uh, long-term, the solution here is
to build more AI tools
that find patterns of people using
the services that no real person would do.
We are allowing the technologists
to frame this as a problem
that they're equipped to solve.
That is... That's a lie.
People talk about AI
as if it will know truth.
AI's not gonna solve these problems.
AI cannot solve the problem of fake news.
Google doesn't have the option of saying,
"Oh, is this conspiracy? Is this truth?"
Because they don't know what truth is.
They don't have a...
They don't have a proxy for truth
that's better than a click.
If we don't agree on what is true
or that there is such a thing as truth,
we're toast.
This is the problem
beneath other problems
because if we can't agree on what's true,
then we can't navigate
out of any of our problems.
We should suggest
Flat Earth Football Club.
Don't show him
sports updates. He doesn't engage.
A lot of people in Silicon Valley
subscribe to some kind of theory
that we're building
some global super brain,
and all of our users
are just interchangeable little neurons,
no one of which is important.
And it subjugates people
into this weird role
where you're just, like,
this little computing element
that we're programming
through our behavior manipulation
for the service of this giant brain,
and you don't matter.
You're not gonna get paid.
You're not gonna get acknowledged.
You don't have self-determination.
We'll sneakily just manipulate you
because you're a computing node,
so we need to program you 'cause that's
what you do with computing nodes.
Oh, man.
When you think about technology
and it being an existential threat,
you know, that's a big claim, and...
it's easy to then, in your mind, think,
"Okay, so, there I am with the phone...
scrolling, clicking, using it.
Like, where's the existential threat?
Okay, there's the supercomputer.
The other side of the screen,
pointed at my brain,
got me to watch one more video.
Where's the existential threat?"
It's not
about the technology
being the existential threat.
It's the technology's ability
to bring out the worst in society...
...and the worst in society
being the existential threat.
If technology creates...
mass chaos,
outrage, incivility,
lack of trust in each other,
loneliness, alienation, more polarization,
more election hacking, more populism,
more distraction and inability
to focus on the real issues...
that's just society.
And now society
is incapable of healing itself
and just devolving into a kind of chaos.
This affects everyone,
even if you don't use these products.
These things have become
digital Frankensteins
that are terraforming the world
in their image,
whether it's the mental health of children
or our politics
and our political discourse,
without taking responsibility
for taking over the public square.
-So, again, it comes back to--
-And who do you think's responsible?
I think we have
to have the platforms be responsible
for when they take over
election advertising,
they're responsible
for protecting elections.
When they take over mental health of kids
or Saturday morning,
they're responsible
for protecting Saturday morning.
The race to keep people's attention
isn't going away.
Our technology's gonna become
more integrated into our lives, not less.
The AIs are gonna get better at predicting
what keeps us on the screen,
not worse at predicting
what keeps us on the screen.
I... I am 62 years old,
getting older every minute,
the more this conversation goes on...
I'm probably gonna be dead and gone,
and I'll probably be thankful for it,
when all this shit comes to fruition.
Because... Because I think
that this scares me to death.
Do... Do you...
Do you see it the same way?
Or am I overreacting to a situation
that I don't know enough about?
I think,
in the... in the shortest time horizon...
civil war.
If we go down the current status quo
for, let's say, another 20 years...
we probably destroy our civilization
through willful ignorance.
We probably fail to meet the challenge
of climate change.
We probably degrade
the world's democracies
so that they fall into some sort
of bizarre autocratic dysfunction.
We probably ruin the global economy.
Uh, we probably, um, don't survive.
You know,
I... I really do view it as existential.
that are gonna know what it was like
before this illusion took place?
Like, how do you wake up from the matrix
when you don't know you're in the matrix?
A lot of what we're saying
sounds like it's just this...
one-sided doom and gloom.
Like, "Oh, my God,
technology's just ruining the world
and it's ruining kids,"
and it's like... "No."
It's confusing
because it's simultaneous utopia...
and dystopia.
Like, I could hit a button on my phone,
and a car shows up in 30 seconds,
and I can go exactly where I need to go.
That is magic. That's amazing.
When we were making the like button,
our entire motivation was, "Can we spread
positivity and love in the world?"
The idea that, fast-forward to today,
and teens would be getting depressed
when they don't have enough likes,
or it could be leading
to political polarization
was nowhere on our radar.
I don't think these guys set out
to be evil.
It's just the business model
that has a problem.
You could shut down the service
and destroy whatever it is--
$20 billion of shareholder value--
and get sued and...
But you can't, in practice,
put the genie back in the bottle.
You can make some tweaks,
but at the end of the day,
you've gotta grow revenue and usage,
quarter over quarter. It's...
The bigger it gets,
the harder it is for anyone to change.
What I see is a bunch of people
who are trapped by a business model,
an economic incentive,
and shareholder pressure
that makes it almost impossible
to do something else.
I think we need to accept that it's okay
for companies to be focused
on making money.
What's not okay
is when there's no regulation, no rules,
and no competition,
and the companies are acting
as sort of de facto governments.
And then they're saying,
"Well, we can regulate ourselves."
I mean, that's just a lie.
That's just ridiculous.
Financial incentives kind of run
the world,
so any solution to this problem
has to realign the financial incentives.
There's no fiscal reason
for these companies to change.
And that is why I think
we need regulation.
The phone company
has tons of sensitive data about you,
and we have a lot of laws that make sure
they don't do the wrong things.
We have almost no laws
around digital privacy, for example.
We could tax data collection
and processing
the same way that you, for example,
pay your water bill
by monitoring the amount of water
that you use.
You tax these companies on the data assets
that they have.
It gives them a fiscal reason
to not acquire every piece of data
on the planet.
The law runs way behind on these things,
but what I know is the current situation
exists not for the protection of users,
but for the protection
of the rights and privileges
of these gigantic,
incredibly wealthy companies.
Are we always gonna defer to the richest,
most powerful people?
Or are we ever gonna say,
"You know, there are times
when there is a national interest.
There are times
when the interests of people, of users,
is actually more important
than the profits of somebody
who's already a billionaire"?
These markets undermine democracy,
and they undermine freedom,
and they should be outlawed.
This is not a radical proposal.
There are other markets that we outlaw.
We outlaw markets in human organs.
We outlaw markets in human slaves.
Because they have
inevitable destructive consequences.
We live in a world
in which a tree is worth more,
financially, dead than alive,
in a world in which a whale
is worth more dead than alive.
For so long as our economy works
in that way
and corporations go unregulated,
they're going to continue
to destroy trees,
to kill whales,
to mine the earth, and to continue
to pull oil out of the ground,
even though we know
it is destroying the planet
and we know that it's going to leave
a worse world for future generations.
This is short-term thinking
based on this religion of profit
at all costs,
as if somehow, magically, each corporation
acting in its selfish interest
is going to produce the best result.
This has been affecting the environment
for a long time.
What's frightening,
and what hopefully is the last straw
that will make us wake up
as a civilization
to how flawed this theory has been
in the first place
is to see that now we're the tree,
we're the whale.
Our attention can be mined.
We are more profitable to a corporation
if we're spending time
staring at a screen,
staring at an ad,
than if we're spending that time
living our life in a rich way.
And so, we're seeing the results of that.
We're seeing corporations using
powerful artificial intelligence
to outsmart us and figure out
how to pull our attention
toward the things they want us to look at,
rather than the things
that are most consistent
with our goals and our values
and our lives.
What a computer is,
is it's the most remarkable tool
that we've ever come up with.
And it's the equivalent of a bicycle
for our minds.
The idea of humane technology,
that's where Silicon Valley got its start.
And we've lost sight of it
because it became the cool thing to do,
as opposed to the right thing to do.
The Internet was, like,
a weird, wacky place.
It was experimental.
Creative things happened on the Internet,
and certainly, they do still,
but, like, it just feels like this,
like, giant mall.
You know, it's just like, "God,
there's gotta be...
there's gotta be more to it than that."
I guess I'm just an optimist.
'Cause I think we can change
what social media looks like and means.
The way the technology works
is not a law of physics.
It is not set in stone.
These are choices that human beings
like myself have been making.
And human beings can change
those technologies.
And the question now is
whether or not we're willing to admit
that those bad outcomes are coming
directly as a product of our work.
It's that we built these things,
and we have a responsibility to change it.
The attention extraction model
is not how we want to treat
human beings.
Is it just me or...
Poor sucker.
The fabric of a healthy society
depends on us getting off
this corrosive business model.
We can demand
that these products be designed humanely.
We can demand to not be treated
as an extractable resource.
The intention could be:
"How do we make the world better?"
Throughout history,
every single time
something's gotten better,
it's because somebody has come along
to say,
"This is stupid. We can do better."
Like, it's the critics
that drive improvement.
It's the critics
who are the true optimists.
Hello.
Um...
I mean, it seems kind of crazy, right?
It's like the fundamental way
that this stuff is designed...
isn't going in a good direction.
Like, the entire thing.
So, it sounds crazy to say
we need to change all that,
but that's what we need to do.
Think we're gonna get there?
We have to.
Um,
it seems like you're very optimistic.
-Is that how I sound?
Yeah, I mean...
I can't believe you keep saying that,
because I'm like, "Really?
I feel like we're headed toward dystopia.
I feel like we're on the fast track
to dystopia,
and it's gonna take a miracle
to get us out of it."
And that miracle is, of course,
collective will.
I am optimistic
that we're going to figure it out,
but I think it's gonna take a long time.
Because not everybody recognizes
that this is a problem.
I think one of the big failures
in technology today
is a real failure of leadership,
of, like, people coming out
and having these open conversations
about things that... not just
what went well, but what isn't perfect
so that someone can come in
and build something new.
At the end of the day, you know,
this machine isn't gonna turn around
until there's massive public pressure.
By having these conversations
and... and voicing your opinion,
in some cases
through these very technologies,
we can start to change the tide.
We can start to change the conversation.
It might sound strange,
but it's my world. It's my community.
I don't hate them. I don't wanna do
any harm to Google or Facebook.
I just want to reform them
so they don't destroy the world. You know?
I've uninstalled a ton of apps
from my phone
that I felt were just wasting my time.
All the social media apps,
all the news apps,
and I've turned off notifications
on anything that was vibrating my leg
with information
that wasn't timely and important to me
right now.
It's for the same reason
I don't keep cookies in my pocket.
Reduce the number of notifications
you get.
Turn off notifications.
Turning off all notifications.
I'm not using Google anymore,
I'm using Qwant,
which doesn't store your search history.
Never accept a video recommended to you
on YouTube.
Always choose.
That's another way to fight.
There are tons of Chrome extensions
that remove recommendations.
You're recommending
something to undo what you made.
Yep.
Before you share, fact-check,
consider the source, do that extra Google.
If it seems like it's something designed
to really push your emotional buttons,
like, it probably is.
Essentially, you vote with your clicks.
If you click on clickbait,
you're creating a financial incentive
that perpetuates this existing system.
Make sure that you get
lots of different kinds of information
in your own life.
I follow people on Twitter
that I disagree with
because I want to be exposed
to different points of view.
Notice that many people
in the tech industry
don't give these devices
to their own children.
My kids don't use social media at all.
Is that a rule,
or is that a...
That's a rule.
We are zealots about it.
We're... We're crazy.
And we don't let our kids have
really any screen time.
I've worked out
what I think are three simple rules, um,
that make life a lot easier for families
and that are justified by the research.
So, the first rule is
all devices out of the bedroom
at a fixed time every night.
Whatever the time is, half an hour
before bedtime, all devices out.
The second rule is no social media
until high school.
Personally, I think the age should be 16.
Middle school's hard enough.
Keep it out until high school.
And the third rule is
work out a time budget with your kid.
And if you talk with them and say,
"Well, how many hours a day
do you wanna spend on your device?
What do you think is a good amount?"
they'll often say
something pretty reasonable.
Well, look, I know perfectly well
that I'm not gonna get everybody
to delete their social media accounts,
but I think I can get a few.
And just getting a few people
to delete their accounts matters a lot,
and the reason why is that that creates
the space for a conversation
because I want there to be enough people
out in the society
who are free of the manipulation engines
to have a societal conversation
that isn't bounded
by the manipulation engines.
So, do it! Get out of the system.
Yeah, delete. Get off the stupid stuff.
The world's beautiful.
Look. Look, it's great out there.
&lrm;（“进入凡人生活的一切强大之物
&lrm;无不具有弊端”）
&lrm;（——索福克勒斯）
&lrm;好 你直接开始吧？
&lrm;好 坐下 能否舒适地坐着
&lrm;还好吗？好了
&lrm;是
&lrm;第一镜 打板
&lrm;要我先从自我介绍开始吗？
&lrm;世界你好 贝利 第三镜
&lrm;-可以了吗？
&lrm;-这是我最讨厌的部分 兄弟
&lrm;我不喜欢这样
&lrm;我2011年到2012年间在脸书工作
&lrm;我是Instagram非常早期的员工
&lrm;我曾任职于谷歌、YouTube
&lrm;苹果、谷歌、推特、Palm
&lrm;我帮助创始了Mozilla Labs
&lrm;后来更多工作于火狐这边
&lrm;在拍吗？大家…
&lrm;很好
&lrm;我曾在推特工作 我在推特的
&lrm;最后一份岗位 是高级副总工程师
&lrm;我曾是Pinterest的总经理
&lrm;在那之前 我在脸书做了五年的
&lrm;盈利总监
&lrm;在推特期间 我用了几年时间
&lrm;运营他们的开发者平台
&lrm;然后我做了消费者产品部长
&lrm;我曾合作发明
&lrm;谷歌硬盘、谷歌邮箱聊天
&lrm;脸书网页和脸书“赞”按钮
&lrm;对 所以我才花了八个月的时间
&lrm;和律师反复周旋
&lrm;真的让我很崩溃
&lrm;我在那里任职的时候 一直觉得
&lrm;总体上 这是积极的力量
&lrm;我现在不确定 自己是否还这样想了
&lrm;出于对道德伦理的担心
&lrm;我于2017年6月离开谷歌
&lrm;不仅是担心谷歌的道德伦理
&lrm;而是对整个产业
&lrm;我很担心
&lrm;非常担心
&lrm;如今 人们很容易忽略一个事实
&lrm;这些工具
&lrm;其实为世界创造了一些美好的东西
&lrm;它们让失去联系的家人重聚
&lrm;找器官捐赠者
&lrm;它们为整个世界带来了
&lrm;有意义的、系统的变革
&lrm;这是这些平台积极的一面
&lrm;我认为我们对它的消极一面
&lrm;过度看轻了
&lrm;对 这些东西 只要你发布
&lrm;它们自己就会存活
&lrm;它们被使用的方式
&lrm;与你当初的预期大相径庭
&lrm;我深信 这些负面的后果
&lrm;不是任何人刻意为之
&lrm;没有任何一个坏人 没有 绝对没有
&lrm;那么问题在哪里？
&lrm;是否有问题？问题在哪里？
&lrm;是 很难给出一个单一的、简明的…
&lrm;我在试着谈论很多不同的问题
&lrm;问题在哪里？
&lrm;NETFLIX 原创纪录片
&lrm;虽然面对越来越多的质疑
&lrm;这些所谓的大型技术公司却越发壮大
&lrm;整个技术产业
&lrm;正在面临全新维度的审查
&lrm;一项新的研究初步揭示了心理健康
&lrm;与社交媒体使用之间的联系
&lrm;来谈谈最新的研究…
&lrm;…的情况 根本没有保险
&lrm;数千万美国人无望地
&lrm;玩电子设备成瘾
&lrm;因为技术 现在你真的能把自己
&lrm;隔离在一个泡泡内 周围都是
&lrm;（你的朋友在照片中圈出了你）
&lrm;与你观点相似的人
&lrm;瘾性就更加恶化了
&lrm;虚假新闻变得更发达了
&lrm;威胁着全世界的社会
&lrm;我们12年多以前创造推特的时候
&lrm;根本没有想到这些
&lrm;官方说 他们没有理由相信
&lrm;俄罗斯网络攻击会停止
&lrm;YouTube被迫专注于清理网站
&lrm;如果你和十几岁的孩子去聊
&lrm;他们是绝对不可能删除抖音的…
&lrm;喂 艾拉 可以帮忙摆桌子吗？
&lrm;有一个严肃的问题
&lrm;社交媒体是否让您的孩子抑郁
&lrm;艾拉 可以帮忙摆桌子吗？
&lrm;整容在青少年中已经十分受欢迎
&lrm;整容医生甚至造出了一种新病征
&lrm;“图片分享畸形征”
&lrm;指的是年轻的患者想做整容手术
&lrm;让自己看上去
&lrm;更接近加了滤镜的自拍中的样子
&lrm;我还是不明白
&lrm;你为什么让她用那东西
&lrm;我能怎么办？
&lrm;我是说 她们班上的其他孩子全都有
&lrm;她才11岁
&lrm;卡桑 没人强迫你用
&lrm;你想和别人切断联系多久 都随你
&lrm;喂 我没有手机也不会和别人
&lrm;切断联系 好吗？我现在就在网上
&lrm;而且 这根本不是实际的联系
&lrm;全都是没用的…
&lrm;监视资本主义
&lrm;已经形成了我们的政治和文化
&lrm;而很多人根本没有察觉
&lrm;伊斯兰国煽动网上的关注者
&lrm;现在 白人至上主义也在这样做
&lrm;最近在印度
&lrm;网络暴民害死了十几个人
&lrm;包括这五个…
&lrm;虚假新闻不只是虚假新闻
&lrm;是有后果的
&lrm;在虚假新闻的时代
&lrm;你要怎么解决传染病？
&lrm;吃中餐会感染新冠病毒吗？
&lrm;我们已经从信息时代
&lrm;过渡到了虚假信息时代
&lrm;我们的民主受到了攻击
&lrm;我说的是：“我认为如今
&lrm;创造出的工具正在开始
&lrm;侵蚀社会正常运转的社交纽带”
&lrm;阿莎愿意接受评论 我们播放视频
&lrm;然后说 “女士们先生们
&lrm;我是特里斯坦·哈里斯”
&lrm;-好
&lrm;-很好
&lrm;就是说 我上来 然后…
&lrm;（人道 技术的新议程）
&lrm;你就说“欢迎各位的到来”
&lrm;今天 我想聊聊技术的一个新议程
&lrm;以及我们为什么要这样做
&lrm;因为如果你问人们
&lrm;“如今的技术产业怎么了？”
&lrm;有一种不满和丑闻的杂音
&lrm;“他们盗用了我们的数据”
&lrm;还有技术成瘾问题
&lrm;有虚假新闻问题 有两极分化问题
&lrm;有些竞选过程被黑客操控的问题
&lrm;但是这些问题的背后
&lrm;是否有一个原因
&lrm;导致这些问题在同时发生？
&lrm;-感觉还行吗？
&lrm;-非常好 好
&lrm;我只是想… 我想让人们看到…
&lrm;在技术产业 正面临着一个问题
&lrm;这个问题连名字都没有
&lrm;这个问题有一个源头…
&lrm;环顾你身边
&lrm;感觉这个世界在逐渐疯狂
&lrm;你要问自己 这是正常的吗？
&lrm;还是我们都中了什么魔咒？
&lrm;（特里斯坦·哈里斯
&lrm;谷歌前设计道德伦理学家）
&lrm;（人道技术中心 合作创始人）
&lrm;我希望更多的人能够理解它的原理
&lrm;因为它不应该
&lrm;只被技术产业的业内知道
&lrm;应该让所有人都知道
&lrm;-你好！
&lrm;-嗨！
&lrm;-特里斯坦 幸会
&lrm;-特里斯坦？
&lrm;-对
&lrm;-太好了 好
&lrm;特里斯坦·哈里斯
&lrm;是谷歌前设计道德伦理学家
&lrm;被称为硅谷最接近良知的人物
&lrm;他呼吁技术产业
&lrm;在产品中引进
&lrm;被他称为“道德伦理设计”的要素
&lrm;搞技术的业内人士
&lrm;极少如此直言不讳
&lrm;特里斯坦·哈里斯相信
&lrm;总有人要这样
&lrm;我在谷歌工作的时候
&lrm;我在谷歌邮箱团队
&lrm;我就开始觉得很疲惫
&lrm;因为我们讨论了很多…
&lrm;收件箱应该长什么样
&lrm;应该是什么颜色
&lrm;我自己感觉对邮件成瘾
&lrm;我觉得有趣的是
&lrm;在谷歌邮箱工作的人
&lrm;没有一个想把它做得不那么致瘾
&lrm;我想：“别人想过这个问题吗？
&lrm;我 没听谁谈论过这个问题”
&lrm;我对技术产业整体感到沮丧
&lrm;感觉我们有点迷路了
&lrm;我真的很努力地去尝试 想办法
&lrm;怎样能从行业内部改变这个问题
&lrm;就在这个时候 我决定做一次展示
&lrm;算是号召大家吧
&lrm;每天我回到家 每一个晚上
&lrm;都要花几个小时去做这件事
&lrm;我的呼吁是 历史上从来没有过50个
&lrm;20到35岁之间的加州白人设计师
&lrm;做出一个能影响20亿人的决定
&lrm;20亿人将会拥有
&lrm;他们从来不曾预料的想法
&lrm;只因为一个谷歌的设计师说
&lrm;“你每天早上醒来
&lrm;屏幕上的通知就是这样工作的”
&lrm;我们作为谷歌
&lrm;有解决这个问题的道德责任
&lrm;我把这个展示
&lrm;发给了在谷歌
&lrm;与我关系最近的15到20个同事
&lrm;我很紧张 我不知道他们会怎样想
&lrm;我第二天去上班的时候
&lrm;多数的电脑上都开着这个展示
&lrm;（注意）
&lrm;那天下午 有400个人同时观看
&lrm;看到的人越来越多
&lrm;我收到整个公司同事发来的各种邮件
&lrm;每一个部门的人都说
&lrm;“我太同意了
&lrm;我看到这个问题正在影响我的孩子
&lrm;我看到这个问题正在影响我身边的人
&lrm;我们应该做点什么 来解决这个问题”
&lrm;我感觉自己
&lrm;好像开启了一场革命之类的
&lrm;后来 我才知道莱利·佩吉
&lrm;那一天在三个不同会议
&lrm;都被人告知这个展示的存在
&lrm;于是这个展示
&lrm;创造了这个文化性的时刻
&lrm;谷歌需要认真对待
&lrm;然后…杳无音讯了
&lrm;2006年 所有人…
&lrm;包括我们在脸书的所有人
&lrm;超级羡慕谷歌
&lrm;羡慕谷歌所创建的一切
&lrm;超级实用的服务
&lrm;据我们当时所知
&lrm;为世界带来了很多好处
&lrm;他们建立了一个平行的造钱机器
&lrm;我们超级羡慕嫉妒谷歌
&lrm;在我们看来太优雅了…
&lrm;太完美了
&lrm;脸书当时才成立大概两年
&lrm;我被雇到脸书 去找出
&lrm;公司未来要走怎样的商业模式
&lrm;我曾是盈利总监 大概意思就是
&lrm;“你是要去想出
&lrm;这个东西怎样盈利的人”
&lrm;当时很多人做了很多工作
&lrm;但我明显是其中一个指向…
&lrm;首先 我们必须要赚钱
&lrm;我认为这个广告模式
&lrm;可能是最优雅的方式
&lrm;妈妈刚给我们发的什么视频？
&lrm;一个脱口秀 不过挺不错的
&lrm;那个人还算是个天才
&lrm;他在谈论删除社交媒体
&lrm;你们真应该这样做
&lrm;我可能要开始屏蔽她的邮件了
&lrm;讲真 我都不知道她在说什么
&lrm;天啊 她还不如我
&lrm;-不 她只用来找菜谱
&lrm;-对 还有工作
&lrm;-还有健身视频
&lrm;-还看我们在做什么
&lrm;还看她这辈子遇到过的每一个人
&lrm;在做什么
&lrm;如果你一边往下划着
&lrm;你的社交媒体推送
&lrm;一边看着我们
&lrm;你需要把你该死的手机放下 听好
&lrm;因为我们的下一位嘉宾
&lrm;写了一本优秀的书
&lrm;书的内容是社交媒体
&lrm;多大程度上破坏了我们的生活
&lrm;掌声有请《立刻删除
&lrm;你社交媒体的十个论点》作者
&lrm;贾伦·拉尼尔
&lrm;谷歌、脸书这样的公司是有史以来
&lrm;最富有、最成功的几个公司
&lrm;他们的员工数量相对较少
&lrm;他们只有一个大电脑 在那里摇钱
&lrm;问题是 别人为什么给他们钱呢？
&lrm;这是一个非常重要的问题
&lrm;我做了35年的技术产业投资者
&lrm;硅谷的前50年 行业制造产品…
&lrm;硬件、软件 卖给顾客
&lrm;简单良好的商业模式
&lrm;过去十年 硅谷最大的公司
&lrm;一直涉足贩卖他们用户的勾当
&lrm;现在这样说 有点陈词滥调
&lrm;但因为我们不为使用这些产品付钱
&lrm;广告商为我们使用的产品付钱
&lrm;广告商是顾客
&lrm;我们是被销售的商品
&lrm;经典的说法是
&lrm;“如果你没有花钱买产品
&lrm;那你就是被卖的产品”
&lrm;（你就是被卖的产品）
&lrm;很多人想：“谷歌只是一个搜索框
&lrm;脸书只是一个看我朋友们在做什么
&lrm;看他们照片的地方”
&lrm;但他们没有意识到的是
&lrm;他们在竞争你的关注
&lrm;脸书、阅后即焚图片分享、推特
&lrm;Instagram、YouTube
&lrm;这种公司 他们的商业模式
&lrm;是让人们的注意力持续吸引在屏幕上
&lrm;我们来想办法 怎样尽最大可能
&lrm;获得这个人的注意力
&lrm;我们能让你在上面花多少时间？
&lrm;我们能让你给我们分出
&lrm;你人生的多少时间？
&lrm;当你去想 这些公司是怎样运作的
&lrm;就能开始想通了
&lrm;网络上有过各种服务
&lrm;我们都认为是免费的
&lrm;但它们并不是免费的
&lrm;是广告商在付钱
&lrm;广告商为什么给这些公司付钱？
&lrm;它们付钱 交换给你展示广告
&lrm;我们是产品 我们的关注
&lrm;就是卖给广告商的产品
&lrm;这样说 过于简单化了
&lrm;产品其实是我们行为和认知的
&lrm;逐渐的、一点一点的
&lrm;我们未察觉到的变化
&lrm;（行为和认知的 变化）
&lrm;这才是产品 是唯一可能的产品
&lrm;这其中 没有任何东西
&lrm;能再被称为产品了
&lrm;这是他们能拿来赚钱的唯一东西
&lrm;改变你做的事
&lrm;你的思维模式 改变你这个人
&lrm;这是一种逐渐的变化 非常轻微
&lrm;如果你去找一个人
&lrm;你说：“给我一千万美元
&lrm;我会让世界往你希望的方向改变1%…”
&lrm;是整个世界！这就很神奇 值很多钱
&lrm;好
&lrm;这是每种商业都一直梦想的
&lrm;就是投放一个广告
&lrm;有一定能够成功的保证
&lrm;这就是他们的生意
&lrm;他们卖的是确定性
&lrm;（确定性）
&lrm;为了在这个生意中成功
&lrm;你必须要有优秀的预判能力
&lrm;（优秀的预判能力）
&lrm;优秀的预判能力始于一个必要条件
&lrm;你需要很多数据
&lrm;（数据）
&lrm;很多人把它称作监视资本主义
&lrm;资本主义利用大型技术公司
&lrm;对每个人去的每一个地方
&lrm;进行无限追踪获利
&lrm;大型技术公司的商业模式
&lrm;是保证广告商能尽最大可能成功
&lrm;这是现在的一种新市场
&lrm;这种市场 以前从未出现过
&lrm;这个市场交易的 只有人类期货
&lrm;就像交易五花肉期货
&lrm;和石油期货的市场
&lrm;我们现在有了
&lrm;交易大范围人类期货的市场
&lrm;这些市场创造了万亿美元
&lrm;让网络公司成为了人类历史上
&lrm;最富有的公司
&lrm;我想让人们知道的是
&lrm;他们在网上做的一切
&lrm;都被监控着 被追踪着 被评估着
&lrm;你所做出的每一个行为
&lrm;都被小心翼翼地监控着、记录着
&lrm;具体到你停在哪一张图片上看了
&lrm;你看了多久
&lrm;是的 真的 看了多久都记录了
&lrm;（纳维亚 参与时间）
&lrm;（瑞恩 参与时间）
&lrm;（雷恩 参与时间）
&lrm;人们孤独的时候 他们知道
&lrm;人们抑郁的时候 他们知道
&lrm;人们看前任爱侣的时候 他们知道
&lrm;你深夜在做什么 他们知道
&lrm;他们全都知道
&lrm;你是内向还是外向
&lrm;你的神经哪种类型
&lrm;你的性格是哪种类型
&lrm;他们所掌握的我们的信息
&lrm;超越人类历史上所有的想象
&lrm;这是史无前例的
&lrm;所有这些我们不经意间
&lrm;不断流露出的数据
&lrm;都被输入到这些系统中
&lrm;几乎不用人类看管
&lrm;会做出越来越好的预判
&lrm;预判出我们要做什么
&lrm;我们是怎样的人
&lrm;（为您推荐）
&lrm;很多人有一种误解 认为被卖掉的
&lrm;是我们的数据
&lrm;脸书的商业兴趣
&lrm;肯定不是放掉这些数据
&lrm;他们用这些数据做什么呢？
&lrm;他们做出预判我们行为的模型
&lrm;拥有最优秀模型的公司就赢了
&lrm;他向下滑网页的速度慢
&lrm;接近他平均阅读一屏时间长度的末尾
&lrm;减少广告加载
&lrm;把朋友和家人弄回来
&lrm;在屏幕的另一端
&lrm;他们就好像拥有一个
&lrm;我们的巫毒娃娃化身一样
&lrm;我们做过的所有事情
&lrm;点击过的每一个地方
&lrm;我们看过的所有视频
&lrm;点赞过的所有内容
&lrm;这些数据都会被返回去
&lrm;用来建造一个越来越精准的模型
&lrm;一旦有了这个模型
&lrm;就能预判这个人做怎样的事
&lrm;好 让我测试一下
&lrm;你将要去哪里
&lrm;我能预判出
&lrm;你会继续看什么样的视频
&lrm;我能预判
&lrm;什么样的情感更能让你产生共鸣
&lrm;好 完美
&lrm;年度最悲壮失败
&lrm;（悲壮失败）
&lrm;-完美 有效果
&lrm;-接着另一个视频
&lrm;漂亮 在它开始之前
&lrm;我们插进去一个运动鞋广告
&lrm;很多这种技术公司有三个主要目标
&lrm;有一个参与度目标
&lrm;增加你的使用 让你一直滑动屏幕
&lrm;有一个增长目标
&lrm;让你不断回来 尽可能多地邀请朋友
&lrm;让他们再邀请更多的朋友
&lrm;还有一个广告目标
&lrm;确保一切按照预期发展
&lrm;我们尽量多地从广告上挣钱
&lrm;每一个目标都由一个算法驱动
&lrm;算法的作用是找出 给你展示什么
&lrm;让数据上涨
&lrm;我们在脸书 经常聊到这个想法
&lrm;能够按照我们的需要调控
&lrm;我们聊过 让马克来调控
&lrm;“喂 我今天想让韩国的用户增加”
&lrm;开始调控
&lrm;“我们调控提高一点广告”
&lrm;“调控提高一点盈利”
&lrm;所以说…
&lrm;所有这些公司
&lrm;都能做到这种程度的精准
&lrm;-兄弟 怎么…
&lrm;-我不知道我怎么没有得到黄牌罚下
&lrm;-那个裁判真是逊
&lrm;-真的是一直…
&lrm;-那是瑞贝卡 去和她说话
&lrm;-我知道那是谁
&lrm;-兄弟 去啊 去跟她说话
&lrm;-我正在努力
&lrm;他的日历上说 他正在休假
&lrm;我们应该实时操作
&lrm;要我给他发一个窗口抖动吗？
&lrm;好 抖吧
&lrm;“您的好友泰勒刚刚加入了
&lrm;去挥手打个招呼吧”
&lrm;快啊 兄弟
&lrm;发一个挥手
&lrm;你都没有… 去和她说话 兄弟
&lrm;您的好友泰勒刚刚加入了！
&lrm;挥手打个招呼吧
&lrm;（联系人网络）
&lrm;新联系人！好 连上了
&lrm;接下来推送
&lrm;用户079044238820瑞贝卡的发帖
&lrm;好主意 卫星定位坐标显示
&lrm;他们距离很近
&lrm;（瑞贝卡 找到了我的灵魂伴侣
&lrm;#闺蜜#呲溜呲溜#好朋友）
&lrm;他容易受到广告影响
&lrm;拍卖时间
&lrm;（广告预览 深度衰落发蜡）
&lrm;卖了！给深度衰落发蜡
&lrm;我们有468个感兴趣的竞标人
&lrm;我们以3.262分卖给本 换来他的印象
&lrm;我们创造了一个世界
&lrm;这个世界中 在线联系变成了主体
&lrm;尤其是对年轻一代
&lrm;然而在这个世界 每次两个人联系
&lrm;唯一能提供经济支持的
&lrm;是通过一个鬼祟的第三方
&lrm;有人给第三方钱 去操纵这两个人
&lrm;所以 我们创造了全球的一整代人
&lrm;他们成长的背景中 交流的意义
&lrm;文化的意义 就是操纵
&lrm;我们所做的每一件事的中心
&lrm;都加入了欺骗和鬼祟
&lrm;（“任何足够先进的技术
&lrm;都极其类似于魔术”）
&lrm;（——亚瑟·C·克拉克）
&lrm;-拿起另一个…
&lrm;-好
&lrm;-放在哪里才有用？
&lrm;-这样很好
&lrm;-这里？
&lrm;-好
&lrm;这会怎样出现在摄影机中
&lrm;如果我要做…
&lrm;-其实 我们可以…
&lrm;-就这样？
&lrm;-什么？
&lrm;-对
&lrm;-再来一次？
&lrm;-没错 好
&lrm;对 不是 可能不是…
&lrm;这样… 对
&lrm;这个就稍微没那么…
&lrm;克里斯在那边已经烦死了
&lrm;可以了吗？
&lrm;（魔术！）
&lrm;我从五岁开始学习变魔术
&lrm;我可以骗过成年人
&lrm;有博士学位的完全成熟的成年人
&lrm;魔术师几乎像是最早期的神经学家
&lrm;和心理学家
&lrm;他们是最先明白
&lrm;人们思想工作原理的人
&lrm;他们在人们身上
&lrm;实时测试着很多很多的东西
&lrm;魔术师懂一些事
&lrm;你思想中
&lrm;你自己都没意识到的某一部分
&lrm;这是让幻觉起作用的关键
&lrm;医生、律师
&lrm;知道怎样构造747飞机或者核弹的人
&lrm;他们并不会比别人更了解
&lrm;自己的思想有多么脆弱
&lrm;因为这是一个完全不用的学科领域
&lrm;这个学科领域 对所有人类都适用
&lrm;（斯坦福大学）
&lrm;从这个角度来说
&lrm;你就能对技术做了什么
&lrm;有一个不同的理解
&lrm;我在斯坦福劝服技术实验室的时候
&lrm;这就是我们所学到的
&lrm;怎样利用我们知道的一切心理学知识
&lrm;什么东西能劝服人们
&lrm;把这个运用到技术中？
&lrm;在座观众中的很多人 已经是天才了
&lrm;我认为这是事实 但我的目标是
&lrm;让你们变成行为改变的天才
&lrm;很多著名的硅谷人物
&lrm;都上过这个课
&lrm;脸书、优步和其他公司的
&lrm;业绩增长关键人物
&lrm;学习怎样让技术更能劝服人们
&lrm;特里斯坦就是其中一个
&lrm;劝服性技术 可以说是极端应用的
&lrm;刻意设计
&lrm;我们真的想去修改一个人的行为
&lrm;我们想让他们这样做
&lrm;我们想让他们继续用手指这样做
&lrm;你往下拉 刷新 最上面就是新的内容
&lrm;再下拉 再刷新 又是新的
&lrm;每一次都是
&lrm;在心理学上 我们称为“正积极强化”
&lrm;你不知道什么时候能刷到
&lrm;或者你是否能刷到什么
&lrm;它的原理就像是赌城的老虎机
&lrm;你有意识地使用产品 还远远不够
&lrm;我想深度侵入你的大脑根部
&lrm;在你脑中植入一个无意识的习惯
&lrm;让你在更深的层次被编程
&lrm;你自己都没有意识到
&lrm;一个叫做詹姆斯·马歇尔的人
&lrm;每一次你在看到老虎机在柜台上
&lrm;你看一眼 你知道如果你过去
&lrm;它可能有东西给你
&lrm;于是你就玩了一下老虎机
&lrm;看你能得到什么 对吧？
&lrm;这不是偶然 这是设计好的手段
&lrm;他把一个金块
&lrm;给了旧金山军队的一个军官
&lrm;别忘了 旧金山的人口数量
&lrm;当时只有…
&lrm;另一个例子是照片圈人
&lrm;如果你收到一封邮件
&lrm;说你朋友刚刚在一张照片中圈出了你
&lrm;你当然会点击那封邮件 看一下照片
&lrm;这不是你能选择忽略的事情
&lrm;他们所利用的
&lrm;是根植于人类本性中的东西
&lrm;你应该问自己的是
&lrm;“这封邮件中
&lrm;为什么没把照片放进来？
&lrm;这样 看照片就会容易很多 ”
&lrm;当脸书发现这个功能之后
&lrm;他们可真是尽情调控
&lrm;因为他们说
&lrm;“这将是增长积极性的绝好方式
&lrm;我们让大家整天在照片中互相圈吧”
&lrm;（本：至少我们中
&lrm;有一个人拍得很好）
&lrm;他评论了
&lrm;很好
&lrm;瑞贝卡收到了 她正在回复
&lrm;好 让本知道她在输入 别让他下线了
&lrm;激活省略号
&lrm;（至少我们中有一个人拍得很好
&lrm;…）
&lrm;太好了 她发布了
&lrm;他在评论 他给她发帖的评论的评论
&lrm;等一下 他停止输入了
&lrm;我们来自动填入
&lrm;表情 他喜欢使用表情
&lrm;（自动完成 参与度）
&lrm;他选择了“火辣”表情
&lrm;我以为他会选择茄子呢
&lrm;有一整个学科
&lrm;这个领域叫做“增长量黑客学”
&lrm;无数工程师团队
&lrm;他们的工作就是黑入人们的心理
&lrm;让他们拥有更多的增长量
&lrm;他们能得到更多的用户注册
&lrm;更高的参与度
&lrm;能让你邀请更多人
&lrm;各种测试、迭代 种种操作之后
&lrm;知道我们发现最重要现象是什么吗？
&lrm;让任何个体在十天内邀请七个朋友
&lrm;（查马斯·帕里哈皮提亚
&lrm;脸书前增长副总裁）
&lrm;就是这个
&lrm;查马斯是脸书早期的增长负责人
&lrm;他在技术领域非常知名
&lrm;因为他首创了很多增长手段
&lrm;这些手段的使用
&lrm;让脸书用户飞速增长
&lrm;后来那些增长手段
&lrm;变成了硅谷的标准战术
&lrm;在优步使用了
&lrm;在很多其他公司也使用了
&lrm;他首创的一个东西
&lrm;就是对功能上的小变化
&lrm;使用科学A/B测试
&lrm;谷歌和脸书这种公司
&lrm;会推出很多小实验
&lrm;他们不断在用户身上测试
&lrm;随着时间发展
&lrm;不停运行这些实验之后
&lrm;就能发展出能让用户
&lrm;做你想让他们做的事
&lrm;的最佳方式
&lrm;这就是操纵
&lrm;你让我感觉自己像是实验室的小白鼠
&lrm;你就是实验室的小白鼠
&lrm;我们所有人都是
&lrm;我们和开发治愈癌症药物的
&lrm;实验室小白鼠又不一样
&lrm;这些实验的最终获益人 不是我们
&lrm;对吧？我们就像僵尸一样
&lrm;他们想让我们看更多的广告
&lrm;让他们挣更多的钱
&lrm;脸书做了一个实验
&lrm;他们称为“海量规模蔓延实验”
&lrm;好吧
&lrm;我们怎样用脸书页面上的潜意识信号
&lrm;来让更多人在中期选举中投票？
&lrm;他们发现 他们能做到
&lrm;他们得出的一个结论是
&lrm;现在我们知道
&lrm;我们能影响现实世界中的行为和情感
&lrm;而根本不用触发用户的意识
&lrm;他们自己完全不知道
&lrm;我们将这些人工智能引擎
&lrm;指回到我们身上
&lrm;来反向编程 什么能引诱我们的回应
&lrm;就很像你在蜘蛛身上模拟神经细胞
&lrm;来看是什么引起它的腿反应
&lrm;就是这种监狱实验
&lrm;我们在实验中 捆绑人们进入矩阵
&lrm;我们从他们的行为中获取金钱和数据
&lrm;用他们的行为牟利
&lrm;我们甚至都不知道 发生了这些
&lrm;我们想在心理学上弄清楚
&lrm;怎样以最快的速度操纵你
&lrm;然后返回给你让你产生兴奋的事物
&lrm;我们在脸书做得非常出色
&lrm;Instagram也这样做了
&lrm;WhatsApp也这样做了
&lrm;阅后即焚图片分享也这样做了
&lrm;推特也这样做了
&lrm;这种东西正是
&lrm;我这种黑客能想出来的
&lrm;因为你在利用人类心理中的脆弱挣钱
&lrm;（希恩·帕克 脸书前总经理）
&lrm;我只是想 我们这些发明者、创造者…
&lrm;有我 有马克 有…
&lrm;Instagram的凯文·斯特罗姆
&lrm;所有这些人…
&lrm;意识里非常清楚 但我们依然利用了
&lrm;自行车问世的时候 没有人不满
&lrm;对吧？所有人都开始用自行车出行
&lrm;没有人说
&lrm;“天啊 我们刚刚毁掉了社会
&lrm;因为自行车能影响人
&lrm;拉远了他们和孩子间的距离
&lrm;他们在毁掉民主的结构
&lrm;人们无法判断真假了”
&lrm;对于自行车
&lrm;我们从来没有说过这种话
&lrm;如果一个东西是工具
&lrm;它就会忠诚地坐在那里
&lrm;耐心等待
&lrm;如果一个东西不是工具
&lrm;它会在你身上有所求
&lrm;引诱你、操纵你 想从你身上获利
&lrm;我们已经走过了
&lrm;以工具为基础的技术环境
&lrm;来到了以致瘾和操纵
&lrm;为基础的技术环境
&lrm;这是技术环境的改变
&lrm;社交媒体
&lrm;不是原地等在那里被使用的工具
&lrm;它有自己的目标
&lrm;有自己的办法去实现这些目标
&lrm;利用你的心理 来对付你
&lrm;（“只有两个行业
&lrm;把他们的客户叫做‘使用者’
&lrm;非法毒品和软件”）
&lrm;（——爱德华·塔夫特）
&lrm;回想几年之前
&lrm;我是Pinterest的总经理
&lrm;我回到家 到家之后就无法放下手机
&lrm;虽然我有两个小孩子 需要我的关爱
&lrm;我在食物储藏室里打字回邮件
&lrm;有时候会看Pinterest
&lrm;我想：“天啊 这真是典型的讽刺
&lrm;我白天去工作
&lrm;构造一个把我当猎物的东西”
&lrm;我无法… 有时候
&lrm;我真的情不自禁使用
&lrm;我最无法摆脱的是推特
&lrm;以前无法摆脱的是Reddit
&lrm;我后来不得不给自己写程序
&lrm;来切断我阅读Reddit的瘾
&lrm;我最成瘾的 可能是邮件
&lrm;真的 我是认真的 我自己能感觉到
&lrm;这很有趣
&lrm;我很清楚 这一切的幕后发生着什么
&lrm;我还是无法控制自己去使用
&lrm;这就有点可怕了
&lrm;即便知道这些手段的原理
&lrm;我还是容易受到它们影响
&lrm;我拿起手机
&lrm;20分钟就不知不觉过去了
&lrm;你晨起排尿之前
&lrm;会看一眼智能手机吗？
&lrm;或者晨起排尿过程中 会看吗？
&lrm;因为只有这两个选择
&lrm;我试过用意志力克制 纯意志力…
&lrm;“我要放下手机
&lrm;我到家之后 要把手机丢在车里”
&lrm;我应该在千万个不同的日子
&lrm;告诉过自己千万次
&lrm;“我不要把手机带到卧室”
&lrm;然后晚上九点到了
&lrm;“哎 我想把手机带进卧室”
&lrm;这就有点…
&lrm;意志力是一种努力
&lrm;兽性在做着另一种努力
&lrm;隆重介绍“厨房保险箱”
&lrm;“厨房保险箱”是革命性的全新发明
&lrm;帮你战胜诱惑的
&lrm;时间锁保鲜盒
&lrm;大卫只需要把各种诱惑
&lrm;放进这个“厨房保险箱”
&lrm;下一步 进行调控 设置时间
&lrm;最后 按下调控 激活锁
&lrm;“厨房保险箱”超级好
&lrm;我们家有 是吧？
&lrm;…电子游戏、信用卡、手机
&lrm;对 有
&lrm;“厨房保险箱”一旦上锁
&lrm;直到计时器归零之前 没办法打开
&lrm;问题是 社交媒体就是一种毒品
&lrm;我们有着基本的生物学欲望
&lrm;去和别人联系
&lrm;这直接影响着
&lrm;奖赏通路中的多巴胺释放
&lrm;这个机制背后 是几百万年的进化
&lrm;让我们聚在一起 群居生活
&lrm;找到伴侣 繁殖我们的物种
&lrm;所以 毫无疑问 社交媒体这种载体
&lrm;它会优化人们之间的联系
&lrm;自然会有致瘾的可能性
&lrm;爸 停！
&lrm;我在晚饭前 还有上千个消息要回
&lrm;消息？
&lrm;我不知道消息是什么
&lrm;-闻起来好香 宝贝
&lrm;-谢谢
&lrm;我想 我们可以用所有五官
&lrm;来享受今晚的晚餐
&lrm;所以我决定
&lrm;今晚的餐桌上不能使用手机
&lrm;好了 交上来
&lrm;-真的吗？
&lrm;-是
&lrm;-好吧
&lrm;-谢谢 本？
&lrm;-好
&lrm;-妈妈是手机海盗
&lrm;-拿走了
&lrm;-妈！
&lrm;晚餐结束前
&lrm;这些手机会安全地放在这里
&lrm;所有人可以安静待着了 好吗？
&lrm;-我能看一眼是谁吗？
&lrm;-不行
&lrm;我去再拿一个叉子
&lrm;谢谢
&lrm;宝贝 不能打开
&lrm;我锁上了一个小时 别动了
&lrm;我们要聊点什么？
&lrm;我们可以聊聊我今天开车
&lrm;身边经过的极端中心政党疯子
&lrm;-算了 弗兰科
&lrm;-怎么了？
&lrm;我不想聊政治
&lrm;-极端中心怎么了？
&lrm;-看吧？他都没明白
&lrm;取决于你问谁
&lrm;这就像是你问：“政治鼓吹怎么了？”
&lrm;艾拉！
&lrm;天啊
&lrm;-需要我去…
&lrm;-嗯
&lrm;我很担心我的孩子们
&lrm;等你们有了孩子
&lrm;我还会担心你们的孩子
&lrm;虽然我有着各种知识储备 各种经验
&lrm;我还是和孩子们争论
&lrm;他们使用手机和电脑的时间
&lrm;我会对我儿子说
&lrm;“你觉得自己会在手机上花多久？”
&lrm;他会说
&lrm;“也就半小时吧 最多半小时了”
&lrm;我觉得比一小时多一点 一个半小时
&lrm;几周之前看了他的屏幕使用报告
&lrm;-是3小时45分
&lrm;-那不是…
&lrm;我觉得没有… 平均每天？
&lrm;-对
&lrm;-我现在去拿来吗？
&lrm;每一天 我都要提醒我的孩子们
&lrm;愉悦和痛苦的平衡
&lrm;多巴胺短缺的状态 上瘾的风险
&lrm;-对
&lrm;-来揭晓真相
&lrm;每天2小时50分
&lrm;-我们看看
&lrm;-其实 我今天用了很多
&lrm;-过去七天
&lrm;-可能这就是原因
&lrm;Instagram 6小时13分
&lrm;好吧 我使用Instagram是最严重的
&lrm;我的屏幕彻底碎了 谢谢你 卡桑
&lrm;“谢谢你 卡桑”是什么意思？
&lrm;你一直让妈妈担心我们的手机问题
&lrm;但其实这根本不是问题
&lrm;我们吃晚餐不需要手机
&lrm;我明白你说的
&lrm;但这又不是什么大事 没什么啊
&lrm;不是什么大事 那就一周别用手机
&lrm;对
&lrm;对 其实 如果你能把那东西
&lrm;收起来一整周…
&lrm;我就给你买一个新的屏幕
&lrm;-从现在开始吗？
&lrm;-现在开始
&lrm;好 成交
&lrm;好 不过你要放在这里 小朋友
&lrm;好 我把它放进去
&lrm;计时开始 我退后了
&lrm;好
&lrm;-计时开始了
&lrm;-一周
&lrm;天啊…
&lrm;你觉得他能做到吗？
&lrm;不知道 走着瞧
&lrm;你吃饭吧 好吗？
&lrm;美好的家庭晚餐！
&lrm;这些技术产品不是由
&lrm;努力保护和培育孩子的
&lrm;儿童心理学家设计的
&lrm;它们的设计 是让这些算法
&lrm;非常擅于给你推荐下一个视频
&lrm;非常擅于让你拍照加滤镜
&lrm;（两个赞）
&lrm;（确定删除吗？否）
&lrm;（是）
&lrm;这些东西不仅在控制
&lrm;他们把注意力花在哪里
&lrm;尤其是社交媒体越来越深入大脑根部
&lrm;夺走孩子们的判断力
&lrm;自我价值和身份
&lrm;（美化我）
&lrm;（莉莉：可爱！）
&lrm;（索薇娅：天啊 好美）
&lrm;（奥利维亚：你太美了）
&lrm;（阿瓦：你把耳朵P大了吗？）
&lrm;（哈哈）
&lrm;我们进化出
&lrm;在意我们社群中的其他人…
&lrm;（布里亚纳：漂亮！）
&lrm;…是否对我们有好印象的机制
&lrm;因为这很重要
&lrm;但我们的进化 需要我们在意
&lrm;一万个人怎么看我们吗？
&lrm;我们的进化
&lrm;不需要每隔五分钟
&lrm;就获得一次社交认可
&lrm;这根本不是我们需要去体验的
&lrm;我们管理自己的生活
&lrm;建立在获得的完美感上
&lrm;因为爱心、点赞、竖起大拇指
&lrm;这些短期的信号
&lrm;给我们奖赏
&lrm;我们把它融合到价值中
&lrm;融合到真相中
&lrm;不论是否虚假 易破碎的人气
&lrm;这是短期的 你需要承认 这让你更加
&lrm;空虚 于是会再次这样做
&lrm;因为这样
&lrm;它会将你逼入这样一个恶性循环
&lrm;你会想：“我接下来要做什么？
&lrm;因为我还想要这种感觉”
&lrm;想一下 这种现象被20亿人复杂化
&lrm;然后想一下 之后人们
&lrm;会怎样回应别人对自己的看法
&lrm;真的… 真的很恶劣
&lrm;真的太恶劣了
&lrm;美国青少年群体中
&lrm;出现了大幅增长的
&lrm;抑郁和焦虑
&lrm;大概就在2011年到2013年开始的
&lrm;这个国家中 每十万名少女中
&lrm;每年因为割腕或者自残
&lrm;进医院接受治疗的人数
&lrm;在2010年到2011年是非常平稳的
&lrm;在那之后 直线上升
&lrm;大一点的少女中 增加了62%
&lrm;（美国非致命性自残住院人数）
&lrm;进入青春期前的少女 增加了189%
&lrm;将近三倍了
&lrm;更可怕的是
&lrm;自杀也呈现出相同的趋势
&lrm;（美国自杀率
&lrm;每百万女孩死亡人数）
&lrm;大一点的少女 15到19岁
&lrm;与本世纪初相比 增长了70%
&lrm;青春期前的少女
&lrm;最开始的比率非常低
&lrm;现在增长了151%
&lrm;这个增长模式 指向了社交媒体
&lrm;（2009年手机上的社交媒体数量）
&lrm;Z代人
&lrm;1996年之后那会儿出生的孩子们
&lrm;那些孩子们是历史上第一代
&lrm;在初中开始使用社交媒体的
&lrm;他们的时间 花在了哪里？
&lrm;他们放学回家 就拿起手机
&lrm;整个一代人都更加焦虑
&lrm;更加脆弱、更加抑郁
&lrm;他们更不愿意冒险
&lrm;他们拿到驾照的比率下降了
&lrm;出去约会过的人数
&lrm;有过任何形式浪漫互动的人数骤减
&lrm;整个一代人 有了真正的改变
&lrm;别忘了 这些人中的每一个
&lrm;每一个住院的人
&lrm;背后都有一个受伤的、惊恐的家庭
&lrm;“天啊 我的孩子们怎么了？”
&lrm;在我看来 问题很显而易见
&lrm;这些服务正在杀人
&lrm;也在导致人们自杀
&lrm;我不认识哪个家长会说
&lrm;“是 我希望我的孩子们 成长过程中
&lrm;感觉被技术设计师操控
&lrm;操控他们的注意力
&lrm;让他们无法完成作业
&lrm;让他们将自己
&lrm;和不切实际的审美标准相对比”
&lrm;没有人希望那样
&lrm;没有一个人
&lrm;我们以前有一些保护措施
&lrm;小孩子们观看周六早间动画片的时候
&lrm;我们关心保护儿童
&lrm;我们会说：“你不能这样
&lrm;给这个年龄段的孩子看广告”
&lrm;然后有了YouTube儿童频道
&lrm;蚕食了注意力经济的全部
&lrm;现在所有的孩子
&lrm;都能看YouTube儿童频道
&lrm;所有的保护措施
&lrm;所有的管理规定都不见了
&lrm;（没有手机的时间）
&lrm;我们在训练、调节整个一代人…
&lrm;我们不自在、孤独、不确定或害怕时
&lrm;有一个自己的数码安慰
&lrm;这有点让我们
&lrm;自己处理这些情绪的能力退化了
&lrm;Photoshop屏幕的另一端
&lrm;没有几千个工程师
&lrm;用通知 用你的朋友
&lrm;用人工智能去预判
&lrm;什么能完美地让你上瘾 引诱你
&lrm;或者操纵你 或者允许广告商
&lrm;去测试六万种不同的文本或颜色
&lrm;（芝加哥反垄断技术会议）
&lrm;…以此来找到
&lrm;怎样能完美地操纵你的思想
&lrm;这是一种全新的力量和影响
&lrm;我想再一次强调 他们使用的
&lrm;玩弄人们的能力
&lrm;让人们成瘾或者受到影响
&lrm;或许这一次是不同的
&lrm;或许他们是不同的
&lrm;报纸问世时 印刷媒体问世时
&lrm;与现在很不同
&lrm;电视问世的时候 与现在很不同
&lrm;当时有三个主要的…
&lrm;-网络
&lrm;-当时 我也想说
&lrm;但我在说 这是一个全新的层次
&lrm;这个新的层次 以前也发生过很多次
&lrm;这只是我们看见的 最新的一个层次
&lrm;有这样一种说法：“我们去适应它
&lrm;我们要学着与这些设备共存
&lrm;就像我们学着
&lrm;和其他所有事物共存一样”
&lrm;但这个说法没有注意到的是
&lrm;有些东西明显是全新的
&lrm;或许这其中最危险的是
&lrm;这是由技术驱动的
&lrm;在成指数地向前发展
&lrm;（计算机处理能力）
&lrm;大体上
&lrm;如果你看从20世纪60年代至今
&lrm;计算机处理能力增长了万亿倍
&lrm;我们身边没有任何其他东西
&lrm;以这个速率增长
&lrm;比如 汽车速度基本上才实现翻倍
&lrm;几乎所有其他的东西都显得微不足道
&lrm;或许最重要的是
&lrm;我们人类… 我们的生理
&lrm;我们的大脑 根本没有丝毫进化
&lrm;（没有手机的时间）
&lrm;人类的思想、身体和体质
&lrm;基本上不会改变了
&lrm;我们可以搞基因工程
&lrm;在未来开发新的人类物种
&lrm;但是现实来讲
&lrm;你生活在大脑这个硬件下
&lrm;已经存在几百万年了
&lrm;然后出现了这样一个屏幕
&lrm;在屏幕的另一端
&lrm;有上千名工程师和超级计算机
&lrm;有着与你不同的目标
&lrm;那么 这个游戏谁能赢呢？谁会赢？
&lrm;我们怎么会输？
&lrm;-我不知道
&lrm;-他在哪里？这太不正常了
&lrm;我给他推送朋友和家人的内容太多
&lrm;他烦了吗？
&lrm;-或许吧
&lrm;-或许是广告太多了
&lrm;不 一定出了严重的问题
&lrm;我们切换到复苏模式吧
&lrm;当你想到人工智能
&lrm;人工智能会毁掉世界
&lrm;你会看到《终结者》 看到施瓦辛格…
&lrm;我会回来的
&lrm;…你会看到无人机 你觉得
&lrm;“人工智能会杀人的”
&lrm;人们忽略的是 人工智能
&lrm;现在已经在运营着当今世界了
&lrm;甚至谈论“人工智能”都只是暗喻
&lrm;在谷歌这种公司 有超级大的房间
&lrm;有些在地下 有些在水下
&lrm;房间里全是电脑
&lrm;无数的电脑 连绵不绝
&lrm;它们互相之间在内部深度连接
&lrm;在运行着极其复杂的程序
&lrm;始终不停地在彼此之间交换信息
&lrm;他们会运行很多不同的程序
&lrm;在同样的机器上 有不同的产品
&lrm;有些东西可以被描述为简单算法
&lrm;有些算法太过复杂
&lrm;就可以被称为“智能”
&lrm;我想说 算法是内嵌在代码中的观点…
&lrm;算法并不是客观的
&lrm;算法被某种成功的定义优化
&lrm;所以 如果你能想象
&lrm;一个商业公司成功的定义
&lrm;需要依靠算法
&lrm;那就是商业利益
&lrm;通常都有利润
&lrm;你给电脑一个目标
&lrm;说“我想要这个结果”
&lrm;电脑自己去学习 怎样实现
&lrm;这是“机器学习”概念的由来
&lrm;所以 每一天 都会更好一点
&lrm;在正确命令获取正确的推送数据
&lrm;让你在这个产品上花的时间越来越多
&lrm;没人能真正明白 为了实现这个目标
&lrm;他们在做什么
&lrm;算法有着自己的思想 虽然是人写的
&lrm;它写出来的目的
&lrm;是你建立一个机器
&lrm;这个机器会自己改变
&lrm;这种公司 员工非常少
&lrm;在脸书、推特和其他公司
&lrm;只有几个人能明白
&lrm;这些系统的工作原理
&lrm;虽然他们不需要完全理解
&lrm;某一条特定的内容 会发生什么
&lrm;作为人类 我们几乎
&lrm;已经失去了对这些系统的控制
&lrm;因为是它们在控制我们看到的信息
&lrm;更多的是它们在控制我们
&lrm;而不是我们控制它们
&lrm;在他的地理区域对他和可以对比的人
&lrm;进行交叉参照
&lrm;他的心理测定相似者
&lrm;在他的地区
&lrm;有13694个和他行为相似的人
&lrm;-他们中盛行什么？
&lrm;-我们需要真实的好东西
&lrm;才能进行有效的复苏
&lrm;因为平常的那些东西已经不起作用了
&lrm;学校那个可爱的姑娘都没用了
&lrm;我的分析显示
&lrm;用极端中心内容搞政治
&lrm;有62.3%的几率能够获得长期参与
&lrm;还不错
&lrm;想用它引导 还不太够
&lrm;好 所以我们已经试过
&lrm;通知给他圈人照片
&lrm;邀请、实事、甚至是瑞贝卡的私信
&lrm;但是用户01265923010呢？
&lrm;是 本点赞了她所有的发帖
&lrm;几个月的所有发帖 真的点了所有
&lrm;然后就没有然后了
&lrm;我算出了通知安娜的内容
&lrm;会有92.3%的复苏概率
&lrm;（新感情）
&lrm;还有她的新朋友
&lrm;（没有手机的时间）
&lrm;（你的前女友有了新感情！）
&lrm;不是吧
&lrm;好吧
&lrm;（安娜与路易斯正在热恋）
&lrm;什么？
&lrm;当！我们回来了！
&lrm;我们继续挣钱 兄弟们
&lrm;好 让他们和整个世界联系起来
&lrm;我给他看所有他可能喜欢的信息
&lrm;你们是否想过
&lrm;这些推送对本是好的吗？
&lrm;-没想过
&lrm;-没有
&lrm;我在你身上下了咒语
&lrm;因为你是我的
&lrm;你最好停止你做的事情
&lrm;我不骗你
&lrm;（A/B测试 极端中心）
&lrm;不 我不骗你
&lrm;你知道我无法忍受
&lrm;你在四处奔跑
&lrm;爸爸 你更清楚
&lrm;我无法忍受 因为你将我放下
&lrm;耶
&lrm;我在你身上下了咒语
&lrm;因为你是我的
&lrm;你是我的
&lrm;想象一下 你在用脸书…
&lrm;你的对手是人工智能
&lrm;它知道你的一切
&lrm;能够预测你未来的举动
&lrm;你对它却一无所知
&lrm;除了上面有猫的视频和出生日期
&lrm;这根本不是公平的竞争
&lrm;本与杰瑞 该走了 孩子？
&lrm;本？
&lrm;本
&lrm;快点
&lrm;该上学了 我们走
&lrm;（人道技术中心）
&lrm;-你今天怎么样？
&lrm;-我很紧张
&lrm;-你紧张吗？
&lrm;-是啊
&lrm;我们都在当心这个时刻
&lrm;当技术会超越人类力量和智慧
&lrm;技术什么时候会超越人类
&lrm;取代我们的工作 比人类更聪明？
&lrm;但有更早的时刻…
&lrm;技术超越人类的弱点时
&lrm;这个超越的点就是上瘾
&lrm;两极分化、激进化、激化愤怒
&lrm;激化虚荣 一切的根源
&lrm;它在压制人类天性
&lrm;在挫伤人性
&lrm;很抱歉
&lrm;我努力让人们明白
&lrm;脸书这种地方的推送
&lrm;有多错误的一种方式
&lrm;是让他们去想想维基百科
&lrm;（新标签页）
&lrm;当你打开一个维基百科网页
&lrm;你和别人看到的东西是一样的
&lrm;（维基百科 自由的百科全书）
&lrm;所以 这是网络上少有的
&lrm;我们统一共享的东西
&lrm;现在 现象一下 维基百科说
&lrm;我们要给每一个人不同的个性化定义
&lrm;有人给我们钱 让我们这样做”
&lrm;维基百科就会监视你 会计算
&lrm;“我要做什么 才能代表一些商业利益
&lrm;让这个人产生一点改变？” 对吧？
&lrm;然后就会改变整个词条
&lrm;你能想象吗？
&lrm;你应该能够想象得到
&lrm;因为在脸书页面上 就是这样的
&lrm;你的YouTube推送 就是这样的
&lrm;当你登录谷歌 输入“气候变化是…”
&lrm;你会看到 根据你所居住的地区不同
&lrm;会出现不同的结果
&lrm;（气候变化是）
&lrm;在某些城市 你会看到自动完成…
&lrm;“气候变化是一场骗局”
&lrm;在其他地方 你将会看到
&lrm;“气候变化是对自然的破坏”
&lrm;这个功能
&lrm;提供的不都是气候变化的真相
&lrm;而是你在哪里进行谷歌搜索
&lrm;以及谷歌对你个人兴趣的了解
&lrm;即便是两个非常亲近的朋友
&lrm;他们两个有着完全相同的朋友圈子
&lrm;他们会认为
&lrm;“我们会看到脸书上的新推送
&lrm;会看到完全相同的更新”
&lrm;但事实远非如此
&lrm;他们会看到完全不同的世界
&lrm;因为这些是基于计算机的计算
&lrm;对每一个人来说 怎样最完美
&lrm;（直播中）
&lrm;想象这件事的一个方式是
&lrm;这是27亿人的《楚门的世界》
&lrm;每一个人都有自己的现实 自己的…
&lrm;事实
&lrm;你觉得楚门为什么到现在都
&lrm;从来没有接近
&lrm;发现他所在世界的真实本质？
&lrm;我们接受了
&lrm;呈现在我们面前的世界就是现实
&lrm;就是这么简单
&lrm;（直播中）
&lrm;随着时间推移 你会有一种错觉
&lrm;觉得每一个人都认同你
&lrm;因为给你推送的新闻中
&lrm;每个人都和你极其相似
&lrm;一旦你达到了这种状态
&lrm;你就很容易被操纵了
&lrm;和你被魔术师操纵 是同样的方式
&lrm;魔术师给你看纸牌魔术 跟你说
&lrm;“选一张牌 哪张都行”
&lrm;你没有意识到的是
&lrm;他们早就给你设好陷阱了
&lrm;于是你选的那张牌
&lrm;是他们想让你选的
&lrm;这就是脸书的工作原理
&lrm;脸书坐在那里说
&lrm;“喂 选择你的朋友
&lrm;选择你关注的联系人”
&lrm;根本是胡扯 它就跟魔术师一样
&lrm;脸书负责给你进行新闻推送
&lrm;我们都不过是
&lrm;在基于不同的一系列事实行事
&lrm;当大范围发生时
&lrm;你就再也无法考虑甚至消化
&lrm;与你所创造的世界观相悖的信息了
&lrm;那就意味着
&lrm;我们其实不是客观、有建设性的个体
&lrm;睁大你的眼睛 别相信谎言！睁大…
&lrm;然后你扫了一眼另一边
&lrm;你开始想
&lrm;“这些人怎么会如此愚蠢？”
&lrm;他们也看到了我不停看到的这些信息
&lrm;他们怎么会看不到相同的信息？
&lrm;问题的答案是
&lrm;“他们没有看到相同的信息”
&lrm;睁大你的眼睛 别相信谎言！
&lrm;共和党人什么样？
&lrm;愚昧无知
&lrm;民主党就是一个犯罪团伙
&lrm;不是真正的政治党派
&lrm;皮尤研究中心一项全新的大型研究
&lrm;对一万名美国成年人进行调查
&lrm;发现我们比任何时候都要分裂
&lrm;个人和政治两极分化达到20年来最高
&lrm;有超过三分之一的共和党人说
&lrm;民主党是对这个国家的威胁
&lrm;民主党超过四分之一的人
&lrm;也这样说共和党
&lrm;我们讨论的很多问题
&lrm;比如政治两极分化
&lrm;在有线电视上大量存在
&lrm;媒体也有着同样的问题
&lrm;整体上来说 他们的商业模式
&lrm;是把我们的关注出售给广告商
&lrm;网络只是一个新的、更有效率的
&lrm;实现方式罢了
&lrm;我曾在YouTube的工作
&lrm;是研究YouTube推荐
&lrm;让我担心的是 我研究的一个算法
&lrm;增加了社会中的两极分化
&lrm;但从观看时间来看
&lrm;这种两极分化
&lrm;在让人们持续在线观看上 极其有效
&lrm;这些老师教这些东西的唯一原因
&lrm;是有人给他们钱 让他们教
&lrm;-太扯了
&lrm;-喂 本杰
&lrm;今天没有足球训练吗？
&lrm;有 我只想看看今天的新闻
&lrm;你去研究一下 极端中心说的任何话…
&lrm;都不会把你看的这个东西称作新闻
&lrm;你总是说一切都那么混乱 确实是
&lrm;但那东西只是政治鼓吹
&lrm;没有一个是真的
&lrm;全都是让你觉得合理
&lrm;本 我很严肃 这些东西对你有害
&lrm;你应该去足球训练
&lrm;我分享这个东西 是因为我在意
&lrm;我在意你被误导 这是不对的 好吗？
&lrm;人们认为算法的设计
&lrm;是给他们真正想要的 但其实不然
&lrm;算法其实是在试图
&lrm;找到几个非常强大的兔子洞
&lrm;试图找到哪一个兔子洞
&lrm;最贴近你的兴趣
&lrm;然后 如果你开始观看其中一个视频
&lrm;它就会不停继续推荐
&lrm;这种情况 并不是有人刻意为之
&lrm;只是推荐系统一直在做而已
&lrm;以至于著名篮球运动员凯里·欧文
&lrm;说他相信地球是平的 后来又道歉
&lrm;因为他把责任推给
&lrm;YouTube的一个兔子洞
&lrm;你点击 YouTube视频
&lrm;它会继续 这个兔子洞能有多深
&lrm;他后来在国家公共广播电台上说
&lrm;“很抱歉我相信了这个
&lrm;我无意误导人们”
&lrm;有人采访了教室中的一群学生
&lrm;他们说
&lrm;“相信地球是圆的人肯定找他谈了”
&lrm;地球平面阴谋论被算法
&lrm;推荐了几亿次
&lrm;很容易去想
&lrm;只有几个愚蠢的人被说服罢了
&lrm;但是算法每一天都在变得更聪明
&lrm;今天 它们说服人们相信 地球是平的
&lrm;但是明天 它们就会说服你相信
&lrm;一个完全虚假的事情
&lrm;11月7日 话题标签‘披萨门’诞生了
&lrm;披萨门…
&lrm;天啊
&lrm;我还是不能百分之百确定
&lrm;这个最初是从哪里来的
&lrm;但是订披萨等于订一个贩卖的人口
&lrm;这个想法
&lrm;由于脸书上的多个小组越来越大
&lrm;脸书推荐引擎开始建议普通用户
&lrm;让他们加入披萨门小组
&lrm;所以 如果一个用户反对疫苗
&lrm;或者相信飞机喷洒重金属阴谋论
&lrm;或者对脸书的算法表示过
&lrm;他们易于相信阴谋论
&lrm;脸熟的推荐引擎
&lrm;就会推荐给他们披萨门小组
&lrm;最终 这件事达到高潮
&lrm;一名男子携枪出现
&lrm;决定他要给披萨店地下室的
&lrm;那些孩子们自由
&lrm;而这个披萨店根本没有地下室
&lrm;-你当时在这个地方做什么？
&lrm;-确保这里什么都没有
&lrm;-什么事？
&lrm;-恋童癖怪圈
&lrm;披萨门 他在说披萨门
&lrm;这是阴谋论在所有社交媒体上
&lrm;到处传播的一个例子
&lrm;社交网络自己的推荐引擎
&lrm;自愿把这个东西推送给
&lrm;这辈子从来没有搜索过
&lrm;“披萨门”的人们
&lrm;（披萨门
&lrm;民主党和恋童癖的深盘披萨）
&lrm;有一个研究 麻省理工的研究
&lrm;说推特上传播的虚假新闻
&lrm;比真实新闻传播速度快六倍
&lrm;当一个人有着高于另一个人
&lrm;六倍的优势 这种世界会是什么样？
&lrm;你可以想象 这些事情有点…
&lrm;将人类行为的基础平面倾斜了
&lrm;让一些行为更难 让一些行为更容易
&lrm;你总是可以自由地走上山坡
&lrm;但是这样做的人越来越少
&lrm;所以大范围内 在整个社会范围内
&lrm;你就是将基础平面倾斜了
&lrm;改变了数十亿人的想法和行为
&lrm;我们创造了一个
&lrm;偏心于虚假消息的体系
&lrm;并不是因为我们想这样做
&lrm;而是因为虚假信息比真实信息
&lrm;能让各个公司
&lrm;赚到更多钱 真实信息比较无聊
&lrm;这是一个
&lrm;利用虚假信息牟利的商业模式
&lrm;允许未受监管的信息传送给更多的人
&lrm;卖出最好的价钱 以此来赚钱
&lrm;因为气候变化？对
&lrm;这是骗局 对 是真的 这才是重点
&lrm;他们谈论这件事情越多
&lrm;就越会将我们分化
&lrm;他们越有力量 就越有控制权
&lrm;脸书有万亿个新闻推送贴
&lrm;他们无法知道哪些是真的
&lrm;哪些是事实…
&lrm;所以当下这个议题 才如此重要
&lrm;传播迅速的 不只是新冠病毒
&lrm;网上有关于这个病毒的大量虚假信息
&lrm;多喝水能将新冠病毒
&lrm;从你身体中冲走的提议
&lrm;是在社交媒体上广泛流传的
&lrm;该病毒的谜题之一
&lrm;这是政府计划的事件
&lrm;创造了这个病毒
&lrm;来模拟世界各国将会如何应对
&lrm;新冠病毒是一场骗局
&lrm;非典 新冠病毒
&lrm;看看这是什么时候制造的 2018年
&lrm;我觉得是美国政府开始的这场闹剧
&lrm;根本没有人生病 没人生病
&lrm;没有人认识哪个人真正生病了
&lrm;或许是政府在利用新冠病毒当借口
&lrm;让所有人留在家
&lrm;因为有其他的事情要发生
&lrm;新冠病毒不会杀人
&lrm;他们是在掩盖5G辐射害死的人
&lrm;（反监视抗议
&lrm;5G/新冠 虚假宣传标题）
&lrm;我们被谣言轰炸
&lrm;人们去毁掉了真实的手机信号塔
&lrm;我们看到俄罗斯和中国
&lrm;传播谣言和阴谋论
&lrm;今天早上 乌克兰的恐慌与抗议…
&lrm;人们不知道什么是真相
&lrm;现在已经闹出人命了
&lrm;那些传播新冠病毒虚假信息的来源
&lrm;积累了5200万人参与
&lrm;你是说 胶银溶液会有效
&lrm;我们这样说吧
&lrm;虽然没有用新冠病毒的毒株测试过
&lrm;我们看到的新冠病毒
&lrm;只是发生在我们信息生态系统中的
&lrm;一个极端案例
&lrm;（惠特默 希特勒）
&lrm;社交媒体放大了增长迅速的谣言
&lrm;和增长迅速的道听途说
&lrm;以至于我们都不知道 什么是真了
&lrm;不管我们关注的是什么问题
&lrm;你还在队里吗？
&lrm;好 如果你想来 我在训练之前
&lrm;先去吃点零食 你要来吗？
&lrm;当我没说
&lrm;当前 十个人当中 有九个人不满意
&lrm;你仔细想想 极端中心和历史上
&lrm;任何政治运动无异
&lrm;我们要站起来反抗
&lrm;我们要站起来反抗这种杂音
&lrm;你是我的人民 我相信你们
&lrm;-极端中心的内容好棒
&lrm;-他非常喜欢
&lrm;运行一个拍卖
&lrm;843个竞标人 他以4.35美分
&lrm;卖给了一个武器生产商
&lrm;我们来宣传一下这些活动
&lrm;这星期晚些时候
&lrm;将在这片地理区域发生的群众集会
&lrm;新的视频博主也安排好了
&lrm;说实话 我告诉你
&lrm;我愿意付出任何代价
&lrm;我说 任何代价
&lrm;-订阅…
&lrm;-本？
&lrm;…记得回来 因为我告诉你们…
&lrm;我后面会有大事件
&lrm;非常大的事件
&lrm;脸书的一个问题是
&lrm;作为一个有劝说性质的工具
&lrm;它或许是史上最伟大的发明
&lrm;现在 你来想象一下 落在独裁者
&lrm;或者集权主义者手中 会怎样
&lrm;如果你想控制你们国家的人民
&lrm;从未有过像脸书这样有效的工具
&lrm;一个问题最大的影响是
&lrm;一些政府和其他不良人士
&lrm;把社交媒体当作武器
&lrm;导致了真实的线下伤害
&lrm;我认为最明显的案例
&lrm;广泛被媒体关注的
&lrm;是缅甸发生的事情
&lrm;（缅甸总统办公室）
&lrm;在缅甸 人们想到网络时
&lrm;他们想到的 是脸书
&lrm;经常发生的事情是 人们买了手机
&lrm;手机店主会提前帮他们下载好脸书
&lrm;帮他们开好账户
&lrm;于是人们拿到手机之后
&lrm;第一个打开的应用
&lrm;他们唯一知道怎样打开的 就是脸书
&lrm;一个新的震惊调查显示
&lrm;脸书日益增长的
&lrm;对抗缅甸仇恨言论的难题
&lrm;（停止杀害穆斯林）
&lrm;脸书真的给军人和其他不良人士
&lrm;一种控制公众言论的新手段
&lrm;并协助煽动
&lrm;针对罗兴亚族穆斯林的暴力
&lrm;包括大屠杀
&lrm;焚烧整个村庄
&lrm;违反人道主义的
&lrm;大规模强奸和其他严重犯罪行为
&lrm;已经导致七十万罗兴亚族穆斯林
&lrm;逃出这个国家
&lrm;这种情绪高涨的鼓吹
&lrm;以前并不是没有出现过
&lrm;只是这个平台实现了
&lrm;让操纵性言论传播变得异常容易
&lrm;也不用花多少钱
&lrm;如果我想操纵竞选
&lrm;我现在可以去脸书上的
&lrm;一个阴谋论小组
&lrm;可以找到一百个人
&lrm;他们深信地球是平的
&lrm;认为我们登月 完全是阴谋论
&lrm;我可以告诉脸书
&lrm;“给我推荐一千个这种用户”
&lrm;脸书会非常开心地发给我
&lrm;几千个这种用户
&lrm;我现在可以给他们讲更多的阴谋论
&lrm;以3.4美分卖了一个印象
&lrm;推广新的极端中心
&lrm;再安排一个广告
&lrm;算法和操纵人的政治家
&lrm;在学习如何激发我们的方面
&lrm;变得非常专业
&lrm;非常擅长制造我们容易接受的
&lrm;虚假新闻 假装这就是事实
&lrm;给我们造成混乱
&lrm;让我们相信这些谎言
&lrm;我们似乎对自己是怎样的人
&lrm;自己的信仰 有越来越少的控制权
&lrm;…来让他们选择站队
&lrm;到处都是谎言
&lrm;这样他们就能保持住权力
&lrm;这样他们就能控制一切
&lrm;他们可以控制我们的思想
&lrm;这样他们就可以保守他们的秘密
&lrm;（质疑真相）
&lrm;（疾控中心承认掩盖疫苗/自闭症）
&lrm;想象一个没有人相信任何真相的世界
&lrm;（疫苗不普适所有人
&lrm;我们的基因就是证据）
&lrm;所有人都相信 政府在骗他们
&lrm;一切都是阴谋论
&lrm;“我不应该相信任何人
&lrm;我痛恨对立面”
&lrm;一切正在向这个方向发展
&lrm;欧洲的政治地震 余震不止
&lrm;这一次 轮到了意大利和西班牙
&lrm;整体上来说 欧洲传统的
&lrm;中间派联合政府失去了大多数人支持
&lrm;同时极左和极右民粹主义政党
&lrm;获得更多支持
&lrm;（中心）
&lrm;退后
&lrm;好  我们走
&lrm;这些账户专门故意试图
&lrm;散播香港政治纷争信息
&lrm;好 本
&lrm;生活在一个全部信息来自于脸书
&lrm;和社交媒体的国家 是什么感觉？
&lrm;民主迅速崩溃
&lrm;六个月
&lrm;芝加哥的混乱发生后
&lrm;抗议者和支持者之间的暴力冲突…
&lrm;民主正面临着信心危机
&lrm;我们看到的 是对全球民主的攻击
&lrm;（极端中心）
&lrm;多数目标国家 都是
&lrm;进行民主选举的国家
&lrm;大范围发生
&lrm;国家行动者、家财万贯的富翁说
&lrm;“我想让肯尼亚动摇
&lrm;我想让喀麦隆动摇
&lrm;安哥拉？只要这么一点钱”
&lrm;巴西上周日举行了一场特别的选举
&lrm;选举动员是社交媒体驱动的
&lrm;我们技术产业的人创造了
&lrm;动摇和侵蚀社会结构的工具
&lrm;所有国家都在同时发生
&lrm;世界各地都在发生
&lrm;德国、西班牙、法国
&lrm;巴西、澳大利亚都有发生
&lrm;一些世界上最发达的国家
&lrm;正在互相爆破
&lrm;他们有什么共同点？
&lrm;基于你当前的了解
&lrm;你相信脸书
&lrm;影响了2016年大选的结果吗？
&lrm;这个问题好难回答
&lrm;你知道 这个…
&lrm;事实是
&lrm;有很多不同的力量在产生影响
&lrm;脸书、推特和谷歌的代表们
&lrm;回到国会山
&lrm;对俄罗斯干预2016年大选问题
&lrm;进行第二天的证词发言
&lrm;第三方政党的操纵没有黑入
&lrm;对吧？俄罗斯没有黑入脸书
&lrm;他们所做的是 利用脸书
&lrm;为合法广告商与合法用户创造的工具
&lrm;用到了罪恶的用途中
&lrm;就像是远程控制的战争
&lrm;一个国家可以操纵另一个国家
&lrm;都不用真正入侵实体边境
&lrm;我们看到这些暴力的画面
&lrm;这是一个被推来推去的垃圾箱…
&lrm;但问题不是你想投票给谁
&lrm;问题是在社会中散播混乱和分歧
&lrm;这是在霍廷顿海滩市的示威…
&lrm;问题是制造了两个对立面
&lrm;丝毫不再听取对方的观点
&lrm;不再想听对方的观点
&lrm;不再相信对方
&lrm;这是仇恨被暴露出
&lrm;并转化成种族暴力的城市
&lrm;（弗吉尼亚紧张局势
&lrm;暴力当天致三人遇害）
&lrm;本！
&lrm;卡桑德拉！
&lrm;-卡桑！
&lrm;-本！
&lrm;过来！
&lrm;举起手 膝盖跪地 快 跪下
&lrm;-冷静……
&lrm;-本！
&lrm;喂！手举起来！
&lrm;转过去 趴地上
&lrm;我们希望这个系统
&lrm;售卖出最高的竞价吗？
&lrm;完全出售民主
&lrm;你可以控制任何你想控制的思想
&lrm;对特定人群设定谎言
&lrm;制造文化战争？
&lrm;我们希望这样吗？
&lrm;我们这个国家的人民…
&lrm;不再和彼此说话了
&lrm;我们这个国家的人民
&lrm;不再和彼此交友了
&lrm;只因为他们在上一次竞选中投票的人
&lrm;我们这个国家的人民孤立了自己
&lrm;只看认同我们的那些频道
&lrm;我今天想传达的信息是
&lrm;部落主义正在毁掉我们
&lrm;它正在撕裂我们这个国家
&lrm;正常的成年人 不可能这样做
&lrm;如果每个人都有权执着于自己的真相
&lrm;就真没有必要妥协
&lrm;没有必要让人们团结了
&lrm;事实上 真的没有必要让人们互动
&lrm;我们需要对现实有一些共同的理解
&lrm;不然 我们就不是一个国家了
&lrm;（扎克伯格先生）
&lrm;所以长期来看 解决办法
&lrm;是建造更多的人工智能工具
&lrm;找到人们使用这些服务的行为模式
&lrm;这是任何一个真人都做不到的
&lrm;我们允许技术专家 把这个当做一个
&lrm;他们有能力解决的问题呈现
&lrm;这是骗人的
&lrm;人们谈论人工智能
&lrm;好像人工智能知道真理一样
&lrm;人工智能无法解决这些问题
&lrm;人工智能无法解决虚假新闻的问题
&lrm;谷歌没有选择去说
&lrm;“这是阴谋论？这是真相吗？”
&lrm;因为它们不知道 真相是什么
&lrm;它们没有真相的代理服务器
&lrm;只有点击
&lrm;如果我们不同意真相
&lrm;或者不同意存在真相
&lrm;我们就完蛋了
&lrm;这是其他问题之下的问题
&lrm;因为如果我们不能认同真相
&lrm;那我们就无法找到
&lrm;我们任何一个问题的解决方法
&lrm;我们应该建议他
&lrm;关注平面地球足球俱乐部
&lrm;别再给他展示运动消息了
&lrm;他不感兴趣
&lrm;硅谷的很多人相信一种理论
&lrm;我们正在建造一些全球的超级大脑
&lrm;我们所有的用户
&lrm;都只是可交互的神经元
&lrm;他们一点都不重要
&lrm;它让人们服从于这样一个奇怪的角色
&lrm;你就像是一个小的编程元素
&lrm;我们通过我们的行为操纵去 编程
&lrm;为了服务于这个巨型大脑
&lrm;你根本不重要
&lrm;不会给你钱 不会告诉你真相
&lrm;你没有自主权
&lrm;我们会鬼祟地操纵你
&lrm;因为你是编程中的结点
&lrm;所以我们需要将你编程
&lrm;因为我们就要这样对待编程中的结点
&lrm;天啊
&lrm;当你想到技术
&lrm;技术是一种人类存亡的威胁
&lrm;这个指控很严重…
&lrm;然后你的脑中就会很容易想
&lrm;“好 我正在拿着手机
&lrm;互动、点击、使用
&lrm;人类存亡的威胁在哪里？
&lrm;好 有一个超级电脑
&lrm;在屏幕的另一端 正指向我的大脑
&lrm;让我再看一个视频
&lrm;人类存亡的威胁在哪里？”
&lrm;技术并不是人类存亡的威胁
&lrm;（劝服性技术 美国参议院听政会）
&lrm;是技术能够把
&lrm;社会中最坏的东西带出来的能力
&lrm;社会中最坏的东西
&lrm;才是人类存亡的威胁
&lrm;（美国参议院）
&lrm;如果技术创造了公众混乱
&lrm;愤怒、无礼
&lrm;彼此缺乏信任
&lrm;孤独、疏远、更加两极分化
&lrm;更多大选黑入、更多平民政治
&lrm;让人更加分散注意力
&lrm;无法集中在真正的问题上…
&lrm;那只是社会
&lrm;现在社会无法自愈
&lrm;转移成了一种混乱的形式
&lrm;这影响着每一个人
&lrm;即使你不使用这些产品
&lrm;这些事情变成了数码的科学怪人
&lrm;让这个世界变成他们现象中的样子
&lrm;不论是儿童的心理健康
&lrm;还是我们的政治 我们的政治演说
&lrm;而不用因为控制公众舆论
&lrm;承担责任
&lrm;-所以 还是要回到…
&lrm;-你觉得这一切怪谁？
&lrm;我认为我们必须让平台负起责任
&lrm;因为他们接管大选广告的时候
&lrm;就要负责保护大选
&lrm;当他们接管儿童心理健康
&lrm;或是儿童频道的时候
&lrm;他们就有责任保护好儿童频道
&lrm;保持人们关注的竞争不会结束
&lrm;我们的技术会在我们生活中更加集成
&lrm;而不会减少
&lrm;人工智能会更加擅长预判
&lrm;什么内容能让我们持续盯着屏幕
&lrm;而不是做出更差的预判
&lrm;我已经62岁了
&lrm;随着这个对话继续进行
&lrm;我每一分钟都在变老
&lrm;但我会告诉你
&lrm;到时候我可能已经死了 不在了
&lrm;但我可能会为此感恩
&lrm;因为当这些恐怖的东西结出恶果
&lrm;我觉得能吓死我
&lrm;你也这样看吗？
&lrm;还是我对一个我不够了解的情况
&lrm;过度反应了？
&lrm;你最担心什么？
&lrm;我认为在最短的时间范围内…
&lrm;是内战
&lrm;如果现在的常态继续下去
&lrm;我们说再过20年
&lrm;我们很可能会因为故意无知
&lrm;毁掉我们的文明
&lrm;我们或许会无法应对气候变化的挑战
&lrm;我们或许会瓦解世界的民主
&lrm;最终衰落成一种奇怪的独裁机能障碍
&lrm;我们或许会毁掉全球经济
&lrm;我们或许会无法存活
&lrm;我真的把它看做
&lrm;人类生死存亡的大问题
&lrm;这会是知道在这种幻象发生之前
&lrm;世界是什么样的最后一代人吗？
&lrm;如果你不知道自己在矩阵中
&lrm;你要怎么从矩阵中醒来？
&lrm;（“不论是乌托邦还是毁灭
&lrm;都是一场一触即发的接力赛…）
&lrm;（直接通往最后一刻…”
&lrm;——巴克敏斯特·富勒）
&lrm;你知道 我们说的很多话
&lrm;听起来像是…
&lrm;片面的悲观
&lrm;“天啊 技术正在毁灭世界
&lrm;正在毁灭孩子们”
&lrm;不是这样的
&lrm;这很困惑
&lrm;因为这同时是乌托邦和毁灭
&lrm;我可以在手机按一个按钮
&lrm;30秒后就能出现一辆车
&lrm;我就可以去想去的任何地方
&lrm;这简直是魔法 太神奇了
&lrm;我们制作“点赞”按钮的时候
&lrm;我们全部的动机是 “我们可以
&lrm;在世界中传播积极和爱吗？”
&lrm;时间快进到当下
&lrm;青少年会因为没有得到足够多的点赞
&lrm;而抑郁 这个想法
&lrm;或者会导致政治两极分化
&lrm;当时是完全无法想象的
&lrm;我不认为这些人
&lrm;最开始的目标是邪恶的
&lrm;只是这个商业模式有问题
&lrm;你可以关掉服务 毁掉不管这是什么
&lrm;200亿美元的股东利益 被起诉…
&lrm;但现实是 覆水难收
&lrm;你可以做出一些小的调整 但是最终
&lrm;你要增加收益和使用
&lrm;每一个季度都要增加
&lrm;规模做得越大 越难让任何人改变
&lrm;我看到的是一群被困住的人
&lrm;被商业模式
&lrm;经济奖励和股东压力困住
&lrm;几乎无法做其他的任何事情
&lrm;我认为我们应该接受
&lrm;公司专注于挣钱 是合情合理的
&lrm;不合情合理的是
&lrm;当没有监管、没有规定、没有竞争
&lrm;公司在充当实际政府部门
&lrm;然后他们说“我们可以监管自己”
&lrm;这肯定是骗人的 怎么可能呢
&lrm;经济奖励可以说运营着世界
&lrm;所以这个问题的任何解决方案
&lrm;一定要符合经济奖励
&lrm;这些公司没有需要改变的财政理由
&lrm;所以我才认为 我们需要监管
&lrm;手机公司有无数的关于你的敏感数据
&lrm;我们有很多法律去保证
&lrm;他们不会利用这些数据做错事
&lrm;在数码隐私上 我们几乎没有立法
&lrm;我们可以对数据收集和处理收税
&lrm;原理等同于你交水费
&lrm;监控你自己的用水量
&lrm;让这些公司因为持有的数据资产交税
&lrm;就能给他们一个财政理由
&lrm;不去获取地球上每一条数据
&lrm;立法在这方面太落后了
&lrm;但据我所知 当前状况的存在
&lrm;不是为了保护用户
&lrm;而是为了保护这些巨型的
&lrm;超级富有公司的权利和特权
&lrm;我们要一直听从最有钱
&lrm;最有权力的人吗？
&lrm;还是我们要说
&lrm;“有时候 确实是有国家利益
&lrm;有时候 人民的利益 用户利益
&lrm;其实比一个
&lrm;已经是亿万富翁的人的利益
&lrm;更加重要？”
&lrm;这些市场削弱了民主 削弱了自由
&lrm;应该对他们进行法律的制裁
&lrm;这不是激进的提议
&lrm;我们有法律制裁的其他市场
&lrm;我们制裁人类器官贩卖市场
&lrm;我们制裁人类奴隶市场
&lrm;因为它们都有不可避免的破坏性后果
&lrm;我们生活的世界
&lrm;死去的树比活着的树更有经济价值
&lrm;这个世界 死去的鲸
&lrm;比活着的鲸更有价值
&lrm;只要我们的经济这样运转
&lrm;公司不受监管
&lrm;它们就会继续破坏树木
&lrm;继续捕杀鲸
&lrm;在地球上挖矿 从地下抽石油
&lrm;虽然我们知道 这样做会破坏地球
&lrm;我们知道 这样做会为未来几代人
&lrm;留下一个更不堪的世界
&lrm;这是目光短浅
&lrm;为了利益牺牲一切的信仰
&lrm;指望每个
&lrm;只顾自己私利的公司会突然神奇地
&lrm;去产生最好的结果
&lrm;这已经影响环境很久了
&lrm;恐怖的是 希望这是
&lrm;压倒骆驼的最后一根稻草
&lrm;让我们作为文明的种族 去幡然醒悟
&lrm;这个理论最初就有很多缺点
&lrm;让我们看到 我们现在就是树 就是鲸
&lrm;我们的关注就是被挖掘的矿产
&lrm;如果我们花时间盯着一个屏幕
&lrm;盯着一个广告 对公司而言
&lrm;比我们用这个时间
&lrm;过自己丰富的生活 更加有利可图
&lrm;我们看到了这样的后果
&lrm;我们看到公司利用强大的人工智能
&lrm;凌驾在我们的智能之上
&lrm;研究怎样拉拢我们的关注
&lrm;让我们去看 他们想让我们看的东西
&lrm;而不是让我们看
&lrm;与我们目标、价值观
&lrm;与我们的生活最为一致的东西
&lrm;（史蒂夫·乔布斯 今日演讲者）
&lrm;电脑对我来说 是…
&lrm;是我们人类历史上 最神奇的发明
&lrm;相当于是我们思想的自行车
&lrm;人道技术的创想 是硅谷最初的目标
&lrm;我们已经背离了这个目标
&lrm;因为这样做比较酷
&lrm;而不是这样做比较正确
&lrm;网络就是一个奇怪的、可笑的地方
&lrm;它是实验性的
&lrm;网络上发生着有创意的事情
&lrm;当然现在也有发生
&lrm;但是感觉像一个巨大的商场
&lrm;就是“天啊
&lrm;肯定不止表面上这么简单”
&lrm;我想我只是一个乐观主义者
&lrm;因为我认为
&lrm;我们可以改变社交媒体的样子和方式
&lrm;技术的工作方式不是物理学定律
&lrm;它不是一成不变的
&lrm;这些都是像我这样的人类
&lrm;做出的选择
&lrm;人类可以改变这些技术
&lrm;现在的问题是 我们是否愿意承认
&lrm;这些后果 是我们杰作的直接产物
&lrm;这些东西是我们建立起来的
&lrm;我们有责任去改变它们
&lrm;提取关注模型
&lrm;不是我们想对待人类的方式
&lrm;只有我这样想吗？还是…
&lrm;可悲的人
&lrm;一个健康社会的结构
&lrm;要依靠我们脱离这种
&lrm;有破坏性的商业模型
&lrm;我们可以要求
&lrm;这些产品进行人道设计
&lrm;不被当做可以提取的资源对待
&lrm;我们的动机可以是
&lrm;“我们怎样让这个世界变得更好？”
&lrm;在整个人类历史中
&lrm;每一次有事物变得更好
&lrm;都是因为有人站出来说
&lrm;“这太蠢了 我们可以做得更好”
&lrm;是批判者驱动着改进
&lrm;批判者才是真正的乐观主义者
&lrm;你好
&lrm;感觉有点疯狂 是吧？
&lrm;这东西的设计基本方式
&lrm;就不会朝着好的方向发展
&lrm;整个社交媒体
&lrm;我说要改变这一切
&lrm;听起来有点疯狂
&lrm;但我们需要这样做
&lrm;你觉得这一天能实现吗？
&lrm;必须要实现
&lrm;你似乎非常乐观
&lrm;听起来是这样吗？
&lrm;是 我是说…
&lrm;我无法相信你一直这样说
&lrm;因为我在想：“真的吗？” 我感觉
&lrm;我们正走向毁灭 而不是乌托邦
&lrm;我感觉我们正在飞速走向毁灭
&lrm;需要一个奇迹
&lrm;才能让我们走下这条路“
&lrm;这个奇迹当然是集体意识
&lrm;可我是乐观主义者
&lrm;我们一定会有办法解决
&lrm;但我认为 可能会用很久的时间
&lrm;因为不是所有的人都意识到了
&lrm;这是一个问题
&lrm;我认为当今技术最大的一个失败
&lrm;是领导力的真正失败
&lrm;人们站出来 去公开讨论
&lrm;不仅是哪些地方进行得好
&lrm;还应该讨论哪里不完美
&lrm;才能让有人介入 构建一些新的东西
&lrm;最终 你知道
&lrm;在有足够的公众压力之前
&lrm;这台机器是绝对不会回头的
&lrm;通过这些对话 发出你的声音
&lrm;在一些情况下 通过某些特定的技术
&lrm;我们可以开始改变趋势
&lrm;我们可以开始改变对话
&lrm;听起来可能有点奇怪
&lrm;但这是我的世界 是我生活的环境
&lrm;我不恨他们
&lrm;我不想伤害谷歌或者脸书
&lrm;我只是想改革它们
&lrm;别让他们毁了世界 你知道吗？
&lrm;我在手机上卸载了很多程序
&lrm;我感觉那些都是浪费时间
&lrm;所有的社交媒体程序 所有的新程序
&lrm;我关掉了通知
&lrm;所有那些让我手机震动的通知
&lrm;不够及时 对现在我来说
&lrm;并不重要的信息
&lrm;也正是因为同样的理由
&lrm;我兜里不放饼干
&lrm;减少你收到的通知数量
&lrm;关掉通知
&lrm;关掉所有应用的通知
&lrm;我已经不再用谷歌了
&lrm;我用Qwant搜索引擎
&lrm;这个引擎不会存储你的搜索历史
&lrm;永远不要接受
&lrm;YouTube上给你推荐的视频
&lrm;永远自己去选择
&lrm;这是另一个抗争的方式
&lrm;谷歌浏览器有无数扩展程序
&lrm;可以移走推荐
&lrm;我很喜欢你推荐一个
&lrm;撤销你所做东西的东西
&lrm;对
&lrm;在你分享之前 查找一下事实
&lrm;思考一下信息来源 谷歌搜索一下
&lrm;如果这个东西感觉像是
&lrm;以触发你的情感按钮为目标
&lrm;很可能确实是
&lrm;基本可以说 你用点击去投票
&lrm;如果你点击了钓鱼链接
&lrm;你就是在创造一个经济奖励
&lrm;延续这个已经存在的体系
&lrm;在你的生活中 一定要获得
&lrm;各种不同的信息
&lrm;我会在推特上关注我不认同的人
&lrm;因为我想看到不同的观点
&lrm;要知道 技术行业中的很多人
&lrm;不会把这些设备给他们自己的小孩用
&lrm;我的孩子们完全不使用社交媒体
&lrm;这是规定 还是…
&lrm;家规
&lrm;我们对它很狂热
&lrm;我们很疯狂
&lrm;我们不会让我们的孩子
&lrm;拥有任何看屏幕的时间
&lrm;我想出了
&lrm;我自己认为的三个简单原则
&lrm;能让生活对家人来说更容易
&lrm;这是经过研究验证的
&lrm;第一个原则是
&lrm;在每晚的固定时间 所有设备
&lrm;不能进入卧室
&lrm;不管是什么时间 睡前半小时
&lrm;所有设备全都拿出去
&lrm;第二个原则是
&lrm;高中之前禁止使用社交媒体
&lrm;我个人认为 这个年龄应该是16岁
&lrm;初中已经够难了 上高中之前别用了
&lrm;第三个原则是
&lrm;和你的孩子研究出一个时间预算
&lrm;如果你和他们聊 去说
&lrm;“你每天想在你的设备上花多少时间
&lrm;你觉得适合的时长是多少”
&lrm;他们通常会说出一个很合理的时长
&lrm;看 我非常清楚
&lrm;我无法让所有人删除社交媒体账号
&lrm;但我想我可以让几个人这样做
&lrm;让几个人删除账号
&lrm;就已经能产生很大影响了
&lrm;理由是 这样能创造一个对话的空间
&lrm;因为我想让社会中有足够的人
&lrm;这些人不受到引擎的操纵
&lrm;能够进行社交对话
&lrm;没有受到操纵引擎的牵制
&lrm;这样做吧！退出这个体系
&lrm;对 删掉 下线这个愚蠢的东西
&lrm;世界很美丽 你们看
&lrm;外面的世界很美好
&lrm;（在社交媒体上关注我们！）
&lrm;（开玩笑的）
&lrm;（我们来聊聊怎样解决这个问题
&lrm;登录TheSocialDilemma.com）
&lrm;字幕翻译：王成成